<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>IACS UR E27</title>
    <link href="https://ure27.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://ure27.com" />
    <updated>2026-01-02T10:53:21+08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>e27 team</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://ure27.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>E26/27 2H2025 recap</title>
        <author>
            <name>e27 team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ure27.com/e2627-2h2025-recap.html"/>
        <id>https://ure27.com/e2627-2h2025-recap.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://ure27.com/media/posts/13/Gemini_Generated_Image_kmtp8okmtp8okmtp.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2026-01-02T10:53:21+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://ure27.com/media/posts/13/Gemini_Generated_Image_kmtp8okmtp8okmtp.jpg" alt="" />
                    Global Maritime Regulatory Compliance Review: IACS UR E26 &amp; E27 Implementation Analysis&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://ure27.com/media/posts/13/Gemini_Generated_Image_kmtp8okmtp8okmtp.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <h1 data-path-to-node="0">Global Maritime Regulatory Compliance Review: IACS UR E26 &amp; E27 Implementation Analysis (H2 2025)</h1>
<h2 data-path-to-node="1">1. Executive Summary</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="2">The second half of 2025 represents a watershed moment in the maritime industry's transition toward a fully cyber-resilient operational framework. Following the mandatory entry into force of the International Association of Classification Societies (IACS) Unified Requirements (UR) E26 and E27 on July 1, 2024, the subsequent twelve months were characterized by initial friction, interpretive ambiguity, and preparatory calibration. However, the period spanning July 1, 2025, to December 31, 2025, has witnessed a definitive maturation of the compliance landscape. The industry has shifted from theoretical preparation to tangible, certified execution, evidenced by a surge in Type Approvals for critical Operational Technology (OT) and the successful delivery of the first generation of "cyber-notated" vessels.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="3">This report provides an exhaustive analysis of the compliance ecosystem during this critical semester. It synthesizes data from classification society rule updates, manufacturer certifications, shipyard announcements, and major industry events to construct a comprehensive picture of the current state of maritime cyber resilience. The analysis reveals that the "compliance lag"—the temporal gap between regulatory mandates and industrial adoption—is rapidly closing, driven by the aggressive mobilization of the supply chain and the rigorous enforcement of new class rules.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="4">A defining characteristic of H2 2025 has been the convergence of cyber resilience with decarbonization. The data indicates a strong correlation between "green" vessel technologies and cyber certification. A significant proportion of the Approvals in Principle (AiP) granted during this period—particularly those unveiled at Gastech 2025—were for next-generation assets such as ammonia-fueled carriers, electric propulsion container ships, and autonomous systems. This suggests that the industry no longer views cyber resilience as a standalone regulatory hurdle but as an intrinsic, non-negotiable quality of the "smart" and "sustainable" vessel transition.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="5">Furthermore, the latter half of 2025 saw the emergence of distinct regional strategies. Japanese stakeholders, led by ClassNK and major manufacturers like Furuno and Nabtesco, have emphasized hardware certification and rigorous guideline adherence. In contrast, the South Korean shipbuilding cluster, dominated by HD Hyundai and Samsung Heavy Industries (SHI), has focused on integrated system approvals that bundle cyber security with complex alternative fuel technologies. Meanwhile, European entities have pioneered the application of these standards in the specialized offshore wind sector.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="6">This report dissects these developments through a structured analysis of regulatory evolution, supply chain dynamics, shipyard integration strategies, and strategic industry events, offering a detailed roadmap of the maritime sector's digital fortification.</p>
<hr data-path-to-node="7">
<h2 data-path-to-node="8">2. Regulatory Evolution and Classification Society Dynamics (H2 2025)</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="9">The enforcement mechanism for IACS URs lies with the individual classification societies. In the latter half of 2025, these organizations moved beyond the initial adoption phase to refine their rule sets, offering granular guidance that addresses the practical challenges encountered during the first year of mandatory compliance. This period was marked by a shift from generic interpretations to specific, operationally adaptable frameworks.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="10">2.1 DNV: The "Fleet-in-Service" and Rule Overhaul</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="11">DNV, maintaining its position as a dominant force in maritime standardization, executed a comprehensive update to its regulatory framework in July 2025. This update was crucial for integrating cyber resilience into the standard vessel lifecycle management, moving it from a design-phase consideration to a continuous operational requirement.</p>
<h4 data-path-to-node="12">2.1.1 July 2025 Rule Edition</h4>
<p data-path-to-node="13"><span data-path-to-node="13,0">The July 2025 edition of DNV's <strong data-path-to-node="13,0" data-index-in-node="31">Rules for Classification of Ships</strong> introduced critical clarifications regarding the <strong data-path-to-node="13,0" data-index-in-node="114">Cyber Secure (Essential)</strong> notation.</span><span data-path-to-node="13,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="1">1</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="13,2"> This notation, which became mandatory for newbuilds contracted after July 1, 2024, is fully aligned with IACS UR E26 and E27. The 2025 update formalized the transition of this requirement from a "new rule" to a standard operational procedure for shipyards and owners.</span></p>
<p data-path-to-node="14"><span data-path-to-node="14,0">One of the most significant structural changes in the 2025 rules was the bifurcation of class notations into <strong data-path-to-node="14,0" data-index-in-node="109">"Design"</strong> and <strong data-path-to-node="14,0" data-index-in-node="122">"In-Operation"</strong> categories.</span><span data-path-to-node="14,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="2">2</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="14,2"> Previously, cyber security notations often conflated technical design features with operational management. The new structure explicitly distinguishes between the physical and technical design of the vessel—covered under the <strong data-path-to-node="14,2" data-index-in-node="226">CYBER SECURE</strong> design notation—and the operational management systems, covered under the <strong data-path-to-node="14,2" data-index-in-node="313">Cyber Security Management System (CSMS)</strong> in-operation notation.</span><span data-path-to-node="14,3"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="2">2</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="14,4"> This nuance is critical for shipowners, as it acknowledges that a vessel designed with robust cyber resilience can still be operated insecurely if management processes fail. It allows for a more targeted compliance assessment, where a lapse in operational procedure does not necessarily invalidate the vessel's design certification.</span></p>
<h4 data-path-to-node="15">2.1.2 Fleet-in-Service Rules (Effective July 2025)</h4>
<p data-path-to-node="16"><span data-path-to-node="16,0">Perhaps the most impactful bureaucratic development was the release of the new <strong data-path-to-node="16,0" data-index-in-node="79">Fleet-in-Service</strong> rules, which became available via the DNV Veracity portal starting June 14, 2025.</span><span data-path-to-node="16,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="2">2</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="16,2"> These rules clarify retention schemes for vessels already in operation. While UR E26 is primarily a newbuild standard, the Fleet-in-Service update provides a clear pathway for "In-Operation" notations to be applied to existing fleets. This creates a bridge for owners who wish to harmonize the cyber posture of their legacy tonnage with their newbuilds, ensuring a consistent fleet-wide security standard.</span></p>
<p data-path-to-node="17"><span data-path-to-node="17,0">The update also introduced the <strong data-path-to-node="17,0" data-index-in-node="31">CO2 RECOND</strong> notation in July 2025.</span><span data-path-to-node="17,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="3">3</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="17,2"> While primarily a decarbonization notation focused on the reconditioning of carbon dioxide for capture and storage, its introduction parallels the cyber updates. The complex process control systems required for CO2 reconditioning fall squarely under the scope of "Essential Systems" in UR E26, highlighting the increasing interdependence of environmental compliance and cyber resilience.</span></p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="18">2.2 ClassNK: The August 2025 Guidelines</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="19">ClassNK (Nippon Kaiji Kyokai) adopted a proactive educational approach in H2 2025. In August 2025, the society released updated editions of its guidelines for both E26 and E27, reflecting the "lessons learned" from the first year of mandatory implementation.</p>
<h4 data-path-to-node="20">2.2.1 Guidelines for Cyber Resilience of Ships (Edition 1.1)</h4>
<p data-path-to-node="21"><span data-path-to-node="21,0">Published in August 2025, Edition 1.1 serves as a detailed commentary on <strong data-path-to-node="21,0" data-index-in-node="73">Part X (UR E26)</strong> of ClassNK's Rules.</span><span data-path-to-node="21,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="4">4</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="21,2"> The revision was driven by a need for "more practical examples" and "enhanced explanations," addressing specific areas of confusion that arose during the initial implementation phase.</span><span data-path-to-node="21,3"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="4">4</sup></span></p>
<p data-path-to-node="22"><span data-path-to-node="22,0">A primary focus of the updated guidelines is the clarification of the document submission process during the <strong data-path-to-node="22,0" data-index-in-node="109">commissioning</strong> phase. This phase is a critical bottleneck where the physical verification of cyber defenses—such as network segmentation tests and access control validation—must occur before vessel delivery. The guidelines provide explicit instructions for <strong data-path-to-node="22,0" data-index-in-node="365">Systems Integrators</strong> (typically the shipyards) on how to document these tests, ensuring that the transition from construction to operation is seamless and compliant.</span><span data-path-to-node="22,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="4">4</sup></span></p>
<h4 data-path-to-node="23">2.2.2 Guidelines for On-Board Systems (UR E27)</h4>
<p data-path-to-node="24"><span data-path-to-node="24,0">Simultaneously, ClassNK updated its guidance for UR E27 in August 2025.</span><span data-path-to-node="24,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="5">5</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="24,2"> This document is critical for manufacturers, as it interprets the <strong data-path-to-node="24,2" data-index-in-node="67">IEC 62443</strong> standards within the context of ClassNK's approval process. The guidelines place a renewed emphasis on the <strong data-path-to-node="24,2" data-index-in-node="184">Secure Development Lifecycle (SDL)</strong> requirements.</span><span data-path-to-node="24,3"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="5">5</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="24,4"> They mandate that suppliers must provide evidence not just that the final product is secure, but that the <i data-path-to-node="24,4" data-index-in-node="107">process used to build it</i> incorporated security at every stage. This includes requirements for secure coding practices, vulnerability testing during development, and rigorous change management procedures.</span></p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="25">2.3 ABS: The "Cyber Resilience (CR)" Expansion</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="26">The American Bureau of Shipping (ABS) focused heavily on extending cyber resilience concepts into the offshore and retrofit markets in H2 2025, demonstrating that compliance is not limited to conventional commercial shipping.</p>
<h4 data-path-to-node="27">2.3.1 The "CR-Ex" Notation</h4>
<p data-path-to-node="28"><span data-path-to-node="28,0">In a landmark development in September 2025, ABS awarded the first <strong data-path-to-node="28,0" data-index-in-node="67">CR-Ex</strong> (Cyber Resilience-Existing) notation to <strong data-path-to-node="28,0" data-index-in-node="113">Jana Marine Services</strong> for three self-elevating units: <i data-path-to-node="28,0" data-index-in-node="166">JANA 505</i>, <i data-path-to-node="28,0" data-index-in-node="176">JANA 508</i>, and <i data-path-to-node="28,0" data-index-in-node="190">JANA 509</i>.</span><span data-path-to-node="28,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="6">6</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="28,2"> This event is significant because it represents the successful migration of E26 principles—originally designed for newbuilds—into the existing fleet. The "Ex" designation explicitly acknowledges that these are not new vessels but have undergone retrofits or procedural upgrades to meet the cyber resilience standards. This signals a growing market appetite for retrofitting cyber compliance, likely driven by charterer requirements in high-value sectors like offshore energy, where asset integrity is paramount.</span></p>
<h4 data-path-to-node="29">2.3.2 Wireless Safety Systems Approval</h4>
<p data-path-to-node="30"><span data-path-to-node="30,0">In October 2025, ABS awarded an <strong data-path-to-node="30,0" data-index-in-node="32">Approval in Principle (AiP)</strong> to <strong data-path-to-node="30,0" data-index-in-node="63">Samsung Heavy Industries (SHI)</strong> for a novel wireless fire and gas detection system.</span><span data-path-to-node="30,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="7">7</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="30,2"> Wireless systems have historically been viewed with caution in cyber resilience frameworks due to their susceptibility to jamming and interception. By granting an AiP, ABS has signaled that wireless safety systems can meet E26 requirements if they employ robust countermeasures, such as proprietary encryption protocols and signal monitoring. This approval challenges traditional hard-wired architectures and opens the door for more flexible, cost-effective safety system designs in the future.</span></p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="31">2.4 Bureau Veritas (BV) and Korean Register (KR)</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="32">Bureau Veritas (BV) and the Korean Register (KR) also made significant strides in H2 2025, focusing on collaborative projects and the integration of cyber standards with green technologies.</p>
<h4 data-path-to-node="33">2.4.1 BV's Dynamic Testing JDP</h4>
<p data-path-to-node="34"><span data-path-to-node="34,0">In December 2025, BV launched a Joint Development Project (JDP) with <strong data-path-to-node="34,0" data-index-in-node="69">Hyundai LNG Shipping</strong> and <strong data-path-to-node="34,0" data-index-in-node="94">Igloo Corporation</strong>.</span><span data-path-to-node="34,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="8">8</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="34,2"> This project is notable because it moves beyond static certification to testing "security policy, monitoring, and response" in an operational environment using Igloo's <strong data-path-to-node="34,2" data-index-in-node="169">SPiDER OT</strong> platform. This represents a shift toward dynamic, real-time compliance monitoring, where the vessel's cyber posture is continuously assessed rather than just checked at delivery.</span></p>
<h4 data-path-to-node="35">2.4.2 KR's Green-Cyber Nexus</h4>
<p data-path-to-node="36"><span data-path-to-node="36,0">Korean Register's announcements, particularly at <strong data-path-to-node="36,0" data-index-in-node="49">Gastech 2025</strong>, underscored the deep connection between cyber resilience and alternative fuels. By certifying the cyber resilience of systems like the <strong data-path-to-node="36,0" data-index-in-node="198">Ammonia Safety System (Hi-CLEARS)</strong> and <strong data-path-to-node="36,0" data-index-in-node="236">LNG Boil-Off Gas (BOG) Treatment</strong> </span><span data-path-to-node="36,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="9">9</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="36,2">, KR is ensuring that the new risks introduced by volatile alternative fuels are managed through secure digital systems.</span></p>
<hr data-path-to-node="37">
<h2 data-path-to-node="38">3. The Supply Chain Revolution: UR E27 Implementation</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="39">The second half of 2025 saw a rapid acceleration in the issuance of Type Approvals for onboard systems. Under IACS UR E27, critical systems (Essential Systems) must be certified for cyber resilience. The diversity of systems receiving approval—from navigation and internal communications to propulsion control and remote monitoring—indicates that the supply chain has largely mobilized to meet the new standards. This "compliance surge" suggests that suppliers who failed to secure certification in the first half of the year are now scrambling to catch up, as shipyards enforce strict vendor lists for post-2024 contracts.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="40">3.1 Navigation and Bridge Systems</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="41">The bridge remains the most interconnected, and therefore most scrutinized, zone on a vessel. Manufacturers in this domain have been among the first to achieve compliance, driven by the immediate need to integrate these systems into newbuild designs.</p>
<ul data-path-to-node="42">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="42,0,0"><span data-path-to-node="42,0,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="42,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Furuno (July 2025):</strong> In July 2025, Furuno announced the completion of its compliance assessment for <strong data-path-to-node="42,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="99">DNV Security Profile 1</strong>.</span><span data-path-to-node="42,0,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="11">11</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="42,0,0,2"> This profile is DNV's specific mapping of IACS UR E27 requirements. Furuno's compliance covers a broad suite of equipment, including the <strong data-path-to-node="42,0,0,2" data-index-in-node="138">FAR-series Radars</strong>, <strong data-path-to-node="42,0,0,2" data-index-in-node="157">ECDIS</strong>, and crucially, the <strong data-path-to-node="42,0,0,2" data-index-in-node="183">HermAce</strong> remote monitoring platform.</span><span data-path-to-node="42,0,0,3"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="12">12</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="42,0,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="42,0,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="42,0,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> The inclusion of "HermAce" is particularly significant. Remote maintenance platforms act as gateways between the ship's trusted OT network and untrusted shore networks. By certifying the platform itself, Furuno secures the entire remote-access conduit, satisfying a key requirement of UR E26 regarding third-party connectivity.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="42,1,0"><span data-path-to-node="42,1,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="42,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">NACOS Platinum (December 2025):</strong> Wärtsilä/NACOS Marine announced that its <strong data-path-to-node="42,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="73">NACOS Platinum Integrated Navigation System (INS)</strong> received DNV Type Approval in December 2025.</span><span data-path-to-node="42,1,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="13">13</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="42,1,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="42,1,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="42,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> This approval explicitly cites compliance with <strong data-path-to-node="42,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="56">IEC 61162-460 Edition 3</strong>, a standard specifically designed for maritime navigation networks. This highlights the "standards interoperability" that manufacturers are leveraging. By adhering to IEC 61162-460, NACOS ensures that its system can be easily integrated into broader shipboard networks while meeting the rigorous segmentation requirements of E27.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="42,2,0"><span data-path-to-node="42,2,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="42,2,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Danelec (July 2025):</strong> On July 1, 2025, Danelec received DNV E27 Type Approval for its <strong data-path-to-node="42,2,0,0" data-index-in-node="85">Onboard Insights</strong> solution.</span><span data-path-to-node="42,2,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="14">14</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="42,2,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="42,2,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="42,2,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> Danelec had previously secured approvals for its Voyage Data Recorders (VDRs). Onboard Insights is a data collection and analytics platform that aggregates high-frequency data from various ship sensors.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="42,2,1,1,0"><i data-path-to-node="42,2,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Significance:</i> As a system that centralizes data flow from multiple critical systems to the cloud, Onboard Insights represents a high-value target. Its certification is vital for shipowners who need to prove that their performance monitoring tools do not introduce vulnerabilities into the vessel's critical infrastructure.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 data-path-to-node="43">3.2 Communication and Safety Systems</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="44">Internal communication systems, previously considered low-risk, are now recognized as critical safety systems requiring E27 compliance. Their integration into the ship's IP network makes them potential vectors for lateral movement if left unsecured.</p>
<ul data-path-to-node="45">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="45,0,0"><span data-path-to-node="45,0,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="45,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Zenitel (November 2025):</strong> In November 2025, Zenitel's <strong data-path-to-node="45,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="53">EXIGO PAGA (Public Address and General Alarm)</strong> system achieved DNV Type Approval (Cyber Secure – Essential).</span><span data-path-to-node="45,0,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="15">15</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="45,0,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="45,0,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="45,0,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> PAGA systems are SOLAS-mandated safety equipment. A cyberattack disabling the alarm system during an emergency could have catastrophic consequences. Zenitel's approval confirms that even audio systems are now being hardened with secure boot, encryption, and strict access controls.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="45,0,1,1,0"><span data-path-to-node="45,0,1,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="45,0,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Restriction:</i> The approval applies <i data-path-to-node="45,0,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="34">only</i> to new deliveries from Zenitel's headquarters in Horten and covers specific hardware and firmware versions. It explicitly excludes existing installations, emphasizing the difficulty and limitations of retrofitting E27 compliance onto legacy hardware.</span><span data-path-to-node="45,0,1,1,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="15">15</sup></span></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="45,1,0"><span data-path-to-node="45,1,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="45,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">MarPoint (H2 2025):</strong> MarPoint's <strong data-path-to-node="45,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="31">Evo2 MultiRouter</strong> and <strong data-path-to-node="45,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="52">UNI Vessel Virtualization Server</strong> achieved ABS Type Approval under UR E27 standards.</span><span data-path-to-node="45,1,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="16">16</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="45,1,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="45,1,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="45,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> The Evo2 MultiRouter acts as the central gateway for vessel communications, managing satellite links and crew internet access. Securing this device is paramount for network segregation (UR E26). The UNI server, which hosts virtual machines for various shipboard applications, represents a modern, consolidated IT/OT architecture. Its certification allows shipowners to deploy virtualized applications with the assurance that the hosting environment meets rigorous cyber resilience standards.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 data-path-to-node="46">3.3 Operational Technology (OT) &amp; Automation</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="47">The engine room and power management systems are the core of UR E26/E27 concern due to the risk of physical damage and loss of propulsion.</p>
<ul data-path-to-node="48">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,0,0"><span data-path-to-node="48,0,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="48,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Høglund (May 2025 / H2 Impact):</strong> Høglund's <strong data-path-to-node="48,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="42">Integrated Automation System (IAS)</strong> received DNV's Cyber Secure (Essential) notation, confirming compliance with Security Profile 1 and IACS UR E27.</span><span data-path-to-node="48,0,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="17">17</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="48,0,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,0,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="48,0,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> The IAS is the brain of the ship's machinery, controlling engines, power management, and cargo systems. Certification of the IAS is a prerequisite for the entire vessel's E26 compliance.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,0,1,1,0"><span data-path-to-node="48,0,1,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="48,0,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Documentation:</i> The approval requires that each delivery be accompanied by a vessel-specific product certificate (PC), based on an assessment of the specific topology and asset inventory for that ship.</span><span data-path-to-node="48,0,1,1,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="18">18</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="48,0,1,1,0,2"> This underscores that E27 is not just a "type" approval but requires per-vessel verification of configuration.</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,1,0"><span data-path-to-node="48,1,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="48,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Kongsberg Maritime (May 2025 / Valid to 2030):</strong> Kongsberg issued a Statement of Compliance for its <strong data-path-to-node="48,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="98">LVD-1/LVD-2 Low Voltage Drives</strong>.</span><span data-path-to-node="48,1,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="19">19</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="48,1,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,1,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="48,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> These drives control propulsion motors and thrusters. For Dynamic Positioning (DP) vessels, the drive controller is effectively the steering system.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,1,1,1,0"><i data-path-to-node="48,1,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Crucial Distinction:</i> The statement explicitly notes: "Regardless of the assessment... an assessment in accordance with UR E26 has to be carried out on a project-specific basis." This highlights a critical friction point in the industry: E27 equipment certification facilitates, but does not automatically grant, E26 vessel compliance. The integration of the certified drive into the ship's specific network architecture must still be verified by the shipyard and class society.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,2,0"><span data-path-to-node="48,2,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="48,2,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Nabtesco (Japan):</strong> Nabtesco's marine engine remote control system (<strong data-path-to-node="48,2,0,0" data-index-in-node="66">M-800 series</strong>) obtained Type Approval from DNV.</span><span data-path-to-node="48,2,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="20">20</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="48,2,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,2,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="48,2,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> This was the first such approval for a Japanese marine equipment manufacturer. As a dominant supplier of engine controls, Nabtesco's compliance ensures that the interface between the bridge and the main engine—one of the most critical conduits on a ship—is secured against manipulation.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="48,3,0"><span data-path-to-node="48,3,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="48,3,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Bachmann:</strong> Bachmann received Bureau Veritas Type Approval for its M200 series controllers.</span><span data-path-to-node="48,3,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="21">21</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="48,3,0,2"> These industrial controllers are widely used in maritime automation. The certificate attests to compliance with relevant standards, ensuring that the foundational hardware used in various automation systems is secure.</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 data-path-to-node="49">3.4 Cybersecurity Solutions (The "Cyber" Supply Chain)</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="50">A new category of "Type Approval" has emerged for software specifically designed to <i data-path-to-node="50" data-index-in-node="84">provide</i> cybersecurity monitoring and management.</p>
<ul data-path-to-node="51">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="51,0,0"><span data-path-to-node="51,0,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="51,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Rakuten Maritime (October 2025):</strong> Rakuten Maritime's cybersecurity solution was honored with the <strong data-path-to-node="51,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="96">SAFETY4SEA Cyber Security Award</strong> in October 2025.</span><span data-path-to-node="51,0,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="22">22</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="51,0,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="51,0,1,0,0"><span data-path-to-node="51,0,1,0,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="51,0,1,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Context:</i> The solution had previously received a ClassNK Innovation Endorsement.</span><span data-path-to-node="51,0,1,0,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="24">24</sup></span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="51,0,1,1,0"><i data-path-to-node="51,0,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Significance:</i> The award recognized its "Secure by Design" strategy and comprehensive compliance with E26/E27. This validates the business model of third-party "Cybersecurity as a Service" providers entering the maritime market. These providers offer the tools (CSMS software, monitoring platforms) that shipowners need to manage their ongoing E26 obligations.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr data-path-to-node="52">
<h2 data-path-to-node="53">4. Shipyard Integration &amp; Newbuild Delivery: UR E26 in Action</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="54">While suppliers focus on E27, the burden of UR E26 falls on the shipyards, acting as Systems Integrators. In H2 2025, major shipyards, particularly in South Korea and Europe, demonstrated their ability to deliver compliant vessels. <strong data-path-to-node="54" data-index-in-node="232">Gastech 2025</strong>, held in Milan from September 9-12, served as a primary stage for these demonstrations.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="55">4.1 HD Hyundai Group: The "Smart Green" Integration</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="56">HD Hyundai (comprising HHI, KSOE, and Mipo) utilized Gastech 2025 to showcase a unified strategy that bundles cyber resilience with advanced green technologies. They effectively communicated that a sustainable ship must also be a secure ship.</p>
<ul data-path-to-node="57">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,0,0"><span data-path-to-node="57,0,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="57,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">16,000 TEU Electric Propulsion Container Ship (September 2025):</strong> HD KSOE and HD HHI received an ABS Approval in Principle (AiP) for this massive electric vessel design.</span><span data-path-to-node="57,0,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="25">25</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="57,0,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,0,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="57,0,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Integration Challenge:</i> An electric ship functions as a massive battery on water, managed entirely by software. The <strong data-path-to-node="57,0,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="115">Battery Management System (BMS)</strong> and <strong data-path-to-node="57,0,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="151">Power Management System (PMS)</strong> are safety-critical OT systems. A cyberattack on these systems could lead to power loss or thermal runaway.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,0,1,1,0"><i data-path-to-node="57,0,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Compliance:</i> The ABS AiP implies that the vessel's electrical architecture was reviewed against ABS's cyber standards, ensuring that the complex data flows controlling the electric propulsion are protected by E26-compliant zones and conduits.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,1,0"><span data-path-to-node="57,1,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="57,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">LNG Boil-Off Gas (BOG) Treatment System (September 2025):</strong> HD HHI and <strong data-path-to-node="57,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="69">Donghwa Pneutec</strong> received a Korean Register (KR) AiP for a new BOG treatment system.</span><span data-path-to-node="57,1,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="9">9</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="57,1,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,1,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="57,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Integration Challenge:</i> BOG systems involve precise pressure and temperature control. Automation failure here can lead to tank overpressure or venting. The automation must be isolated from general IT networks to prevent external manipulation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,1,1,1,0"><i data-path-to-node="57,1,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Compliance:</i> The KR approval under E27 (for the system) allows it to be integrated into E26-compliant LNG carriers, providing a "pre-validated" block for the shipyard to insert into the vessel's larger cyber architecture.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,2,0"><span data-path-to-node="57,2,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="57,2,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">IoT-Based Smart Accommodation System (September 2025):</strong> HD Hyundai Mipo received a KR AiP for this crew welfare system.</span><span data-path-to-node="57,2,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="6">6</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="57,2,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,2,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="57,2,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Integration Challenge:</i> This directly addresses the "Crew Welfare" vector, which E26 brings into scope if connected to the ship's network. Securing IoT devices in crew quarters (smart lights, HVAC control) is notoriously difficult due to the proliferation of consumer-grade hardware.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,2,1,1,0"><i data-path-to-node="57,2,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Compliance:</i> The AiP suggests a managed architecture where the crew welfare network is strictly segmented (via VLANs and firewalls) from the vessel's operational backbone, allowing for comfort without compromising safety.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,3,0"><span data-path-to-node="57,3,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="57,3,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Ammonia Safety System (Hi-CLEARS) (September 2025):</strong> HD HHI and KSOE received KR AiP for this system.</span><span data-path-to-node="57,3,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="10">10</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="57,3,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,3,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="57,3,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Integration Challenge:</i> Ammonia is highly toxic. The release mitigation system is a critical life-safety system. It relies on sensors to detect leaks and trigger scrubbers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="57,3,1,1,0"><i data-path-to-node="57,3,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Compliance:</i> Cyber resilience is essential to prevent false negatives (masking a leak) or false positives (triggering shutdowns unnecessarily). The certification ensures the integrity of the sensor data and the availability of the control logic.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 data-path-to-node="58">4.2 Samsung Heavy Industries (SHI)</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="59">SHI focused on certifying specific safety and maintenance technologies that support the broader smart ship ecosystem.</p>
<ul data-path-to-node="60">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="60,0,0"><span data-path-to-node="60,0,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="60,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Wireless Fire &amp; Gas Detection (October 2025):</strong> ABS awarded an AiP to SHI for a novel <strong data-path-to-node="60,0,0,0" data-index-in-node="84">wireless</strong> fire and gas detection system.</span><span data-path-to-node="60,0,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="7">7</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="60,0,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="60,0,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="60,0,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Innovation:</i> Wireless systems introduce unique risks, such as signal jamming or spoofing (Layer 1/2 attacks), which are generally frowned upon in strict cyber frameworks.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="60,0,1,1,0"><i data-path-to-node="60,0,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Compliance:</i> Obtaining an AiP for a wireless safety system in the post-E26 era is a major technical achievement. It implies that SHI demonstrated robust countermeasures—such as proprietary encryption, frequency hopping, and continuous signal health monitoring—that satisfied ABS's concerns about "Casual or Coincidental Access" (a key E27 requirement).</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="60,1,0"><span data-path-to-node="60,1,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="60,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Condition-Based Maintenance (November 2025):</strong> SHI's condition-based maintenance system received certification (likely from LR or DNV).</span><span data-path-to-node="60,1,0,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="26">26</sup></span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="60,1,1">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="60,1,1,0,0"><i data-path-to-node="60,1,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Compliance:</i> CBM systems require the continuous export of data from ship machinery to shore-based analytics platforms. This "trusted-to-untrusted" gateway is a focal point of any E26 review. The certification ensures that the data diode or gateway used prevents any reverse flow of malicious traffic from the shore to the ship's engines.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 data-path-to-node="61">4.3 North Star &amp; VARD: Offshore Wind Resilience</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="62"><span data-path-to-node="62,0">The delivery of the <strong data-path-to-node="62,0" data-index-in-node="20">Grampian Kestrel</strong> </span><span data-path-to-node="62,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="26">26</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="62,2"> serves as a prime case study for European compliance in the specialized offshore sector.</span></p>
<ul data-path-to-node="63">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="63,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="63,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">The Vessel:</strong> Built by VARD for North Star, the <i data-path-to-node="63,0,0" data-index-in-node="46">Grampian Kestrel</i> is a Commissioning Service Operation Vessel (CSOV).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="63,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="63,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Operational Context:</strong> CSOVs are highly automated vessels that use Dynamic Positioning (DP) to hold station next to wind turbines. They serve as "floating data centers," connecting physically to turbines and digitally to wind farm control networks.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="63,2,0"><strong data-path-to-node="63,2,0" data-index-in-node="0">Compliance:</strong> The vessel achieved Lloyd's Register's (LR) E26 certification. This was not just a box-ticking exercise but a commercial necessity. Wind farm operators (the clients) demand that connecting vessels do not introduce cyber risks into their critical infrastructure. The E26 notation provides this assurance, proving that cyber resilience is now a "license to operate" in the renewable energy supply chain.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr data-path-to-node="64">
<h2 data-path-to-node="65">5. Strategic Event Analysis: Gastech 2025</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="66"><span data-path-to-node="66,0"><strong data-path-to-node="66,0" data-index-in-node="0">Gastech 2025</strong>, held in Milan from September 9-12, 2025 </span><span data-path-to-node="66,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="28">28</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="66,2">, emerged as the single most significant event for maritime technology news in the second half of the year. It effectively functioned as a "Cyber Shipping" conference, despite its energy focus.</span></p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="67">5.1 The Catalyst for Approvals</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="68">The sheer volume of cyber-related announcements at Gastech 2025 (HD Hyundai's multiple AiPs, DNV's awards, KR's green technology certifications) illustrates that the industry was holding back major validations to present them on this global stage. The event served as a forcing function, driving shipyards and class societies to finalize approvals in time for the show.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="69">5.2 Thematic Convergence</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="70">The event highlighted the inextricable link between the energy transition and digitalization. Every major cyber announcement was tied to a new fuel or propulsion technology (Electric, Ammonia, LNG). The message from Gastech 2025 was clear: <strong data-path-to-node="70" data-index-in-node="240">You cannot build the ships of the future with the analog mindset of the past.</strong> The complexity of managing alternative fuels requires advanced digital control systems, and those systems require advanced cyber protection.</p>
<hr data-path-to-node="71">
<h2 data-path-to-node="72">6. The Intersection of Decarbonization and Cyber Resilience</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="73">A critical insight from H2 2025 is the correlation between <strong data-path-to-node="73" data-index-in-node="59">decarbonization</strong> and <strong data-path-to-node="73" data-index-in-node="79">cyber resilience</strong>. The data suggests that UR E26 is effectively becoming a supporting regulation for the IMO's Greenhouse Gas (GHG) strategy.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="74">6.1 Alternative Fuels as Digital Risks</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="75">New fuels like ammonia and hydrogen require vastly more complex monitoring and safety automation than traditional heavy fuel oil.</p>
<ul data-path-to-node="76">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="76,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="76,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Ammonia:</strong> Requires toxic gas detection, scrubber automation, and precise temperature control.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="76,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="76,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Electric Propulsion:</strong> Requires millisecond-level management of power loads and battery cell health.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="76,2,0"><strong data-path-to-node="76,2,0" data-index-in-node="0">Wind-Assist:</strong> Requires automated control of sails/rotors based on wind data.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p data-path-to-node="77">All of these are OT systems. Therefore, a "Green" ship is by definition a "Digital" ship, and thus a "Cyber-exposed" ship. The widespread certification of these green technologies under E26/E27 frameworks in H2 2025 confirms that the industry has accepted this reality.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="78">6.2 The "CO2 RECOND" Example</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="79"><span data-path-to-node="79,0">DNV's introduction of the <strong data-path-to-node="79,0" data-index-in-node="26">CO2 RECOND</strong> notation in July 2025 </span><span data-path-to-node="79,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="3">3</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="79,2"> is a perfect example. While technically a process notation for carbon capture, the systems it covers (compressors, liquefaction plants) are high-consequence OT. Their inclusion in the rule set necessitates their inclusion in the vessel's cyber asset inventory and risk assessment, effectively merging environmental and digital compliance.</span></p>
<hr data-path-to-node="80">
<h2 data-path-to-node="81">7. Retrofit and Fleet-in-Service: The Existing Fleet Challenge</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="82">While UR E26 focuses on newbuilds, H2 2025 saw the first serious moves to address the existing fleet.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="83">7.1 The CR-Ex Precedent</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="84"><span data-path-to-node="84,0">ABS's award of the <strong data-path-to-node="84,0" data-index-in-node="19">CR-Ex</strong> notation to Jana Marine's liftboats </span><span data-path-to-node="84,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="7">7</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="84,2"> challenges the notion that E26 is only for new ships. It suggests that for high-value assets operating in critical infrastructure (like offshore oil and gas fields), charterers are beginning to demand cyber resilience standards comparable to newbuilds. This could trigger a wave of "voluntary" retrofits in 2026, as owners of older tonnage seek to remain competitive against newer, cyber-certified rivals.</span></p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="85">7.2 Fleet-in-Service Rules</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="86"><span data-path-to-node="86,0">DNV's updated Fleet-in-Service rules </span><span data-path-to-node="86,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="2">2</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="86,2"> provide the administrative framework for this transition. By defining clear "In-Operation" notations, DNV has given shipowners a tool to demonstrate the cyber hygiene of their existing fleets, focusing on management systems (CSMS) even if the hardware cannot be fully upgraded to E26 standards.</span></p>
<hr data-path-to-node="87">
<h2 data-path-to-node="88">8. Future Outlook (2026-2030)</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="89">Based on the trajectory observed in late 2025, several strategic trends are likely to define the next phase of maritime cyber resilience.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="90">8.1 Port State Control (PSC) Integration</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="91">With the major class societies (DNV, ClassNK) having solidified their "In-Operation" rules, the next logical step is regulatory enforcement at the port level. It is anticipated that Port State Control regimes will begin to include Cyber Security Management Systems (CSMS) in their inspection criteria, likely leveraging the new class notations as prima facie evidence of compliance.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="92">8.2 The "System of Systems" Integration Crisis</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="93">As more E27-certified equipment arrives at shipyards in 2026, the burden shifts entirely to the integrators. The industry will likely face challenges in getting diverse certified systems (e.g., a Furuno radar, a Wärtsilä engine, and a Zenitel alarm) to communicate securely without breaking the encrypted "handshakes" required by their individual E27 profiles. This will drive a demand for standardized, cross-vendor security protocols.</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="94">8.3 The Rise of "Cybersecurity as a Product"</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="95"><span data-path-to-node="95,0">The success of companies like Rakuten Maritime </span><span data-path-to-node="95,1"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="23">23</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="95,2"> and Hanwha Systems </span><span data-path-to-node="95,3"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="29">29</sup></span><span data-path-to-node="95,4"> suggests a booming market for third-party cybersecurity solutions. Shipowners, lacking internal cyber expertise, will increasingly outsource their CSMS management to these specialized providers, effectively buying "compliance as a service."</span></p>
<p data-path-to-node="96">In conclusion, the second half of 2025 marked the maritime industry's successful pivot from planning to execution. The regulatory frameworks have been stress-tested and refined, the supply chain has mobilized, and the first generation of compliant vessels is entering service. Cyber resilience has ceased to be a theoretical discussion; it is now a fundamental, operational reality of modern shipping.</p>
<hr data-path-to-node="97">
<h2 data-path-to-node="98">9. Appendix: Summary of Key Compliance Milestones (H2 2025)</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="99">The following table summarizes the significant compliance events, certifications, and rule updates that occurred in the second half of 2025, providing a quick reference to the "news" data points underpinning this analysis.</p>
<div class="horizontal-scroll-wrapper">
<table data-path-to-node="100">
<thead>
<tr>
<td><strong>Date</strong></td>
<td><strong>Entity</strong></td>
<td><strong>Compliance Type</strong></td>
<td><strong>System / Vessel / Rule</strong></td>
<td><strong>Class Society</strong></td>
<td><strong>Source</strong></td>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,1,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,1,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">July 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,1,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,1,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">DNV</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,1,2,0">Rule Update</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,1,3,0">Fleet-in-Service &amp; Main Rules (Cyber Secure Essential)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,1,4,0">N/A</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,1,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="1">1</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,2,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,2,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">July 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,2,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,2,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Furuno</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,2,2,0">Type Approval (E27)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,2,3,0">Security Profile 1 (Nav/Comms/HermAce)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,2,4,0">DNV</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,2,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="11">11</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,3,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,3,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">July 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,3,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,3,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Danelec</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,3,2,0">Type Approval (E27)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,3,3,0">Onboard Insights</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,3,4,0">DNV</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,3,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="14">14</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,4,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,4,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Aug 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,4,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,4,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">ClassNK</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,4,2,0">Guideline Update</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,4,3,0">Guidelines for E26 &amp; E27 (Edition 1.1 / 2.0)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,4,4,0">N/A</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,4,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="4">4</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,5,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,5,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Sept 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,5,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,5,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">HD Hyundai</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,5,2,0">AiP (E26 Context)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,5,3,0">16,000 TEU Electric Propulsion Ship</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,5,4,0">ABS</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,5,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="25">25</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,6,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,6,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Sept 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,6,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,6,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">HD Hyundai</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,6,2,0">AiP (E27 Context)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,6,3,0">LNG BOG Treatment System</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,6,4,0">KR</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,6,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="9">9</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,7,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,7,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Sept 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,7,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,7,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">HD Hyundai</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,7,2,0">AiP (E27 Context)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,7,3,0">Smart Accommodation System</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,7,4,0">KR</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,7,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="6">6</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,8,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,8,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Sept 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,8,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,8,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">HD Hyundai</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,8,2,0">AiP (E27 Context)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,8,3,0">Ammonia Safety System (Hi-CLEARS)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,8,4,0">KR</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,8,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="10">10</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,9,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,9,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Sept 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,9,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,9,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Jana Marine</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,9,2,0">Notation (Retrofit)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,9,3,0">CR-Ex (Existing Vessel) - JANA 505/508/509</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,9,4,0">ABS</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,9,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="7">7</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,10,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,10,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Oct 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,10,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,10,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Rakuten</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,10,2,0">Award</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,10,3,0">E26/E27 Security Solution</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,10,4,0">ClassNK</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,10,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="23">23</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,11,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,11,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Oct 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,11,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,11,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">SHI</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,11,2,0">AiP</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,11,3,0">Wireless Fire/Gas Detection System</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,11,4,0">ABS</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,11,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="7">7</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,12,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,12,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Nov 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,12,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,12,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Zenitel</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,12,2,0">Type Approval (E27)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,12,3,0">EXIGO PAGA System</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,12,4,0">DNV</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,12,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="15">15</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,13,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,13,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Dec 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,13,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,13,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">NACOS</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,13,2,0">Type Approval (E27)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,13,3,0">Platinum INS (IEC 61162-460)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,13,4,0">DNV</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,13,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="13">13</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,14,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,14,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Dec 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,14,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,14,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">BV / Hyundai</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,14,2,0">JDP Launch</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,14,3,0">Cyber Resilience Testing (SPiDER OT)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,14,4,0">BV</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,14,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="8">8</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,15,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,15,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">H2 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,15,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,15,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">MarPoint</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,15,2,0">Type Approval (E27)</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,15,3,0">Evo2 MultiRouter &amp; UNI Server</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,15,4,0">ABS</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,15,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="16">16</sup></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,16,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,16,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">H2 2025</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,16,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="100,16,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Bachmann</strong></span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,16,2,0">Type Approval</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,16,3,0">M200 Controller Series</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,16,4,0">BV</span></td>
<td><span data-path-to-node="100,16,5,0"><sup class="superscript" data-turn-source-index="21">21</sup></span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Sources:</p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now available: July 2024 edition of the DNV class rules for ships ..., </span><a href="https://www.dnv.com/news/2024/now-available-july-2024-edition-of-the-dnv-class-rules-for-ships-and-offshore-units/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.dnv.com/news/2024/now-available-july-2024-edition-of-the-dnv-class-rules-for-ships-and-offshore-units/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">New DNV Fleet-In-Service rules available from 14 June 2025, </span><a href="https://www.dnv.com/news/2025/new-dnv-fleet-in-service-rules-available-from-14-june-2025/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.dnv.com/news/2025/new-dnv-fleet-in-service-rules-available-from-14-june-2025/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DNV rules updated with world first CO 2 reconditioning notation, </span><a href="https://www.dnv.com/news/2025/ma_09072025-dnv-rules-updated-with-world-first-co-2-reconditioning-notation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.dnv.com/news/2025/ma_09072025-dnv-rules-updated-with-world-first-co-2-reconditioning-notation/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Resilience of SHIPS - ClassNK, </span><a href="https://www.classnk.or.jp/hp/pdf/activities/cybersecurity/gl_CyberResilienceofShips_202508e.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.classnk.or.jp/hp/pdf/activities/cybersecurity/gl_CyberResilienceofShips_202508e.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Guidelines for Cyber resilience of on-board systems and equipment ..., </span><a href="https://www.classnk.or.jp/hp/pdf/activities/cybersecurity/gl_cyber_resilience_of_onboard_systems_and_equipment_e202508.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.classnk.or.jp/hp/pdf/activities/cybersecurity/gl_cyber_resilience_of_onboard_systems_and_equipment_e202508.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Surveillance &amp; Maritime News for September 2025, </span><a href="https://www.maritimeinformed.com/news/dt/september-2025.html?page=2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.maritimeinformed.com/news/dt/september-2025.html?page=2</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">American Bureau Of Shipping Maritime News - Marine Link, </span><a href="https://www.marinelink.com/companies/american-bureau-of-shipping-86638"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.marinelink.com/companies/american-bureau-of-shipping-86638</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hyundai LNG, Igloo, and BV launch cyber JDP, </span><a href="https://smartmaritimenetwork.com/2025/12/02/hyundai-lng-igloo-and-bv-launch-cyber-jdp/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://smartmaritimenetwork.com/2025/12/02/hyundai-lng-igloo-and-bv-launch-cyber-jdp/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HD Hyundai's LNG BOG treatment system AIP - Maritime Informed, </span><a href="https://www.maritimeinformed.com/news/hd-hyundai-lng-bog-treatment-system-co-1623926422-ga-co-1636383494-ga-co-1686127340-ga.1757656950.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.maritimeinformed.com/news/hd-hyundai-lng-bog-treatment-system-co-1623926422-ga-co-1636383494-ga-co-1686127340-ga.1757656950.html</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">KR AIP for ammonia ship safety with Hi-CLEARS - Maritime Informed, </span><a href="https://www.maritimeinformed.com/news/kr-aip-ammonia-ship-safety-hi-clears-co-1623926422-ga-co-1636383494-ga-co-1686127340-ga.1757659026.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.maritimeinformed.com/news/kr-aip-ammonia-ship-safety-hi-clears-co-1623926422-ga-co-1636383494-ga-co-1686127340-ga.1757659026.html</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furuno Successfully Completes Compliance Assessment for DNV, </span><a href="https://maritime-executive.com/corporate/furuno-successfully-completes-compliance-assessment-for-dnv"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://maritime-executive.com/corporate/furuno-successfully-completes-compliance-assessment-for-dnv</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furuno successfully completed compliance assessment for DNV ..., </span><a href="https://www.furuno.co.jp/en/news/general/general_category.html?itemid=1674&amp;dispmid=961"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.furuno.co.jp/en/news/general/general_category.html?itemid=1674&amp;dispmid=961</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NACOS Platinum INS Achieves DNV 460-Network Cyber-Secure ..., </span><a href="https://www.nacosmarine.com/post/nacos-platinum-integrated-navigation-system-receives-dnv-type-approval-for-full-460-network-cyber-secure-compliance-under-iacs-e27"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.nacosmarine.com/post/nacos-platinum-integrated-navigation-system-receives-dnv-type-approval-for-full-460-network-cyber-secure-compliance-under-iacs-e27</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Danelec Onboard Insights Solution Receives DNV E27 Cyber ..., </span><a href="https://www.theoceanspace.com/post/danelec-onboard-insights-solution-receives-dnv-e27-cyber-security-type-approval"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.theoceanspace.com/post/danelec-onboard-insights-solution-receives-dnv-e27-cyber-security-type-approval</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EXIGO PAGA Cyber Approval | DNV Certified Maritime Safety - Zenitel, </span><a href="https://www.zenitel.com/news/exigo-paga-cyber-approval"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.zenitel.com/news/exigo-paga-cyber-approval</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ABS Certifies Evo2 and UNI for Cyber Resilience - Marpoint, </span><a href="https://marpoint.gr/news/abs-certifies-evo2-and-uni-for-cyber-resilience/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://marpoint.gr/news/abs-certifies-evo2-and-uni-for-cyber-resilience/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Høglund Accomplishes DNV Cyber Secure Certification, </span><a href="https://hoglund.no/press-release/h%C3%B8glund-accomplishes-dnv-cyber-secure-certification"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://hoglund.no/press-release/h%C3%B8glund-accomplishes-dnv-cyber-secure-certification</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TYPE APPROVAL CERTIFICATE - Høglund, </span><a href="https://hoglund.no/library/library/Static-Files/Cyber-Security-Approval-DNV.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://hoglund.no/library/library/Static-Files/Cyber-Security-Approval-DNV.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Statement of Compliance - Kongsberg, </span><a href="https://www.kongsberg.com/globalassets/kongsberg-maritime/documents/certificates/product/low-voltage-drives/tso_24-024978.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.kongsberg.com/globalassets/kongsberg-maritime/documents/certificates/product/low-voltage-drives/tso_24-024978.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nabtesco's marine engine remote control system obtain type ..., </span><a href="https://www.nabtesco.com/en/news/20250219-16213/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.nabtesco.com/en/news/20250219-16213/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TYPE APPROVAL CERTIFICATE - Bachmann electronic, </span><a href="https://www.bachmann.info/media/2863/download/Bachmann_BV_Type_Approval_M200_en_REV_D0_2025.pdf?v=3"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.bachmann.info/media/2863/download/Bachmann_BV_Type_Approval_M200_en_REV_D0_2025.pdf?v=3</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rakuten Maritime Wins Cyber Security Award at 10th SAFETY4SEA ..., </span><a href="https://global.rakuten.com/corp/news/update/2025/1001_01.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://global.rakuten.com/corp/news/update/2025/1001_01.html</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maritime Leaders recognized at the 2025 SAFETY4SEA Awards, </span><a href="https://maritimes.gr/en/maritime-leaders-recognized-at-the-2025-safety4sea-awards/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://maritimes.gr/en/maritime-leaders-recognized-at-the-2025-safety4sea-awards/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rakuten Maritime Receives Innovation Endorsement from ClassNK ..., </span><a href="https://global.rakuten.com/corp/news/press/2025/0403_01.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://global.rakuten.com/corp/news/press/2025/0403_01.html</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ABS approves HD KSOE electric ship design at Gastech 2025, </span><a href="https://www.maritimeinformed.com/news/abs-approves-hd-ksoe-electric-ship-design-gastech-2025-co-1623926422-ga-co-1635153457-ga-co-1636383494-ga-co-1636534643-ga.1757491821.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.maritimeinformed.com/news/abs-approves-hd-ksoe-electric-ship-design-gastech-2025-co-1623926422-ga-co-1635153457-ga-co-1636383494-ga-co-1636534643-ga.1757491821.html</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">News Content Hub - North Star offshore windfarm support ... - Riviera, </span><a href="https://www.rivieramm.com/news-content-hub/news-content-hub/north-star-certifies-offshore-windfarm-support-vessels-to-iacs-cyber-resilience-standards-84611"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.rivieramm.com/news-content-hub/news-content-hub/north-star-certifies-offshore-windfarm-support-vessels-to-iacs-cyber-resilience-standards-84611</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">First Cyber-Resilient Vessels and Award-Winning Cable-Laying ..., </span><a href="https://maritime-innovations.com/first-cyber-resilient-vessels-and-award-winning-cable-laying-vessel-set-new-standards/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://maritime-innovations.com/first-cyber-resilient-vessels-and-award-winning-cable-laying-vessel-set-new-standards/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gt25 T C Conference Brochure | PDF | Natural Gas - Scribd, </span><a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/896923932/Gt25-t-c-Conference-Brochure"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.scribd.com/document/896923932/Gt25-t-c-Conference-Brochure</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hanwha Systems cybersecurity solution gains ABS type approval, </span><a href="https://www.marinelog.com/legal/safety-and-security/hanwha-systems-cybersecurity-solution-gains-abs-type-approval/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.marinelog.com/legal/safety-and-security/hanwha-systems-cybersecurity-solution-gains-abs-type-approval/</span></a></li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>2026: Perfect storm?</title>
        <author>
            <name>e27 team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ure27.com/2026-perfect-storm.html"/>
        <id>https://ure27.com/2026-perfect-storm.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://ure27.com/media/posts/12/Gemini_Generated_Image_uagp6wuagp6wuagp.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2025-12-30T23:22:15+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://ure27.com/media/posts/12/Gemini_Generated_Image_uagp6wuagp6wuagp.png" alt="" />
                    The 2026 Market Access Cliff: The Year "Compliance" Determines Survival for Marine&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://ure27.com/media/posts/12/Gemini_Generated_Image_uagp6wuagp6wuagp.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <h2 class="align-center">The 2026 Market Access Cliff: The Year "Compliance" Determines Survival for Marine Suppliers.</h2>
<p data-path-to-node="5">On July 1, 2024, the IACS UR E26 and E27 regulations entered into force. For the past 18 months, many equipment manufacturers have treated this as a future problem—a box to check on a roadmap.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="6">But a dangerous hypothesis is proving true: <strong data-path-to-node="6" data-index-in-node="44">2026 will be the "Market Access Cliff" for maritime suppliers.</strong></p>
<p data-path-to-node="11">For manufacturers of sub-systems (Tier 2/3)—such as controllers, sensors, and auxiliary monitoring equipment—IACS UR E27 represents a fundamental shift in how "seaworthiness" is defined.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="12">Historically, your Type Approval focused on vibration, temperature, and electrical safety. As of July 2024, if your device includes a microprocessor or software and communicates data, it now requires a <strong data-path-to-node="12" data-index-in-node="202">Cyber Resilience</strong>.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="7">While shipyards are the ones building the vessels, the crushing pressure of the 2026 timeline will land squarely on the shoulders of the supply chain. Here is why 2026 is the year that divides the industry into "Certified Vendors" and "Former Vendors."</p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="8">The Lag Effect: Why the Crisis Hits in 2026</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="9">To understand the danger, suppliers must look at the shipyard’s schedule, not their own.</p>
<ul data-path-to-node="10">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="10,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="10,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">July 2024:</strong> Mandatory requirement for new ship contracts.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="10,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="10,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">2025:</strong> Detailed design and procurement. Shipyards issue purchase orders (POs) with "E27 Compliance" clauses.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="10,2,0"><strong data-path-to-node="10,2,0" data-index-in-node="0">2026 (The Cliff):</strong> <strong data-path-to-node="10,2,0" data-index-in-node="18">Factory Acceptance Tests (FAT) and Hardware Delivery.</strong></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 data-path-to-node="14">The Supply Chain "Domino Effect"</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="15">Tier 2/3 suppliers often assume cyber regulations apply only to the shipyard or the main navigation system providers (Tier 1). This is factually incorrect due to the structure of the new rules.</p>
<ol start="1" data-path-to-node="16">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="16,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="16,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">The Tier 1 Problem:</strong> Major system integrators (providing engines, bridge systems, or power management) cannot certify their systems under IACS UR E26 unless the sub-components they purchase from <i data-path-to-node="16,0,0" data-index-in-node="194">you</i> are secure.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="16,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="16,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">The SEA Procurement Shift:</strong> Shipyards in Singapore, Vietnam, and Indonesia building for international owners are under pressure to deliver compliant vessels. They are pushing this liability down the chain.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="16,2,0"><strong data-path-to-node="16,2,0" data-index-in-node="0">The Result:</strong> You may receive updated technical specifications requiring "E27 Compliance" not because the shipyard wants it, but because the Tier 1 integrator refuses to connect your uncertified device to their network.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>For suppliers in the Southeast Asia region, where cost-efficiency is paramount, this new requirement poses a specific risk: <strong data-path-to-node="13" data-index-in-node="124">Disqualification by Tier 1 Integrators.</strong></p>
<h3 data-path-to-node="17">The 2026 Delivery Bottleneck</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="18">Most component suppliers operate on shorter lead times than major equipment manufacturers. However, the certification process for E27 is currently taking 6–12 months due to a lack of authorized auditors in the SEA region.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="19">If your product is slated for a vessel delivering in 2026, the certification process must effectively begin now.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="20"><strong data-path-to-node="20" data-index-in-node="0">The Risk:</strong> Shipyards and Tier 1 buyers will not delay a vessel delivery for a sensor or pump controller. If your current product lacks the E27 certificate during the detailed design phase (2025), buyers will likely switch to a competitor who has already secured the paperwork, even at a slightly higher price point, to avoid integration risks.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="22">If your organisation has no prior cybersecurity capabilities, "E27 Compliance" can be demystified into three standard engineering steps, similar to environmental testing:</p>
<ol start="1" data-path-to-node="23">
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="23,0,0"><strong data-path-to-node="23,0,0" data-index-in-node="0">Documentation (The "Paper" Phase):</strong> You must produce a list of all software versions and hardware components (inventory). You do not need a large IT team for this; it is an engineering task.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="23,1,0"><strong data-path-to-node="23,1,0" data-index-in-node="0">Hardening (The "Settings" Phase):</strong> You must prove your device is locked down (e.g., no default passwords like "admin/1234," unused ports are closed). This is a firmware update, not a complete redesign.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p data-path-to-node="23,2,0"><strong data-path-to-node="23,2,0" data-index-in-node="0">Testing (The "Lab" Phase):</strong> Just as you send equipment to a lab for heat testing, you must now engage a Class Society or accredited lab to scan the device for vulnerabilities.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 data-path-to-node="24">Conclusion</h3>
<p data-path-to-node="25">For Tier 2/3 suppliers, E27 is not about becoming a "cybersecurity company." It is about maintaining your license to sell.</p>
<p data-path-to-node="26">The market in Southeast Asia is shifting. The "low-cost" option is no longer viable if it carries "high compliance risk." The goal for 2026 is to ensure your product remains the standard choice for Tier 1 integrators by having the necessary Approval certificates ready before the purchase order is issued.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Navigating the Digital Shoals</title>
        <author>
            <name>e27 team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ure27.com/navigating-the-digital-shoals-tier-2-and-tier-3-supplier-adoption-of-iacs-ur-e27-in-the-southeast-asian-maritime-ecosystem.html"/>
        <id>https://ure27.com/navigating-the-digital-shoals-tier-2-and-tier-3-supplier-adoption-of-iacs-ur-e27-in-the-southeast-asian-maritime-ecosystem.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://ure27.com/media/posts/11/Gemini_Generated_Image_fcje9rfcje9rfcje.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Supplier"/>
            <category term="SEA"/>
            <category term="E27"/>

        <updated>2025-12-30T15:02:59+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://ure27.com/media/posts/11/Gemini_Generated_Image_fcje9rfcje9rfcje.png" alt="" />
                    Tier 2 and Tier 3 Supplier Adoption of IACS UR E27 in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://ure27.com/media/posts/11/Gemini_Generated_Image_fcje9rfcje9rfcje.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <h2>Tier 2 and Tier 3 Supplier Adoption of IACS UR E27 in the Southeast Asian Maritime Ecosystem</h2>
<h3><strong>Executive Summary: The Cyber Resilience Mandate and the Supply Chain Shock</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The global maritime industry stands at a precipice of a fundamental structural transformation, precipitated not by a shift in trade routes or propulsion technologies, but by the imposition of a digital mandate: the International Association of Classification Societies (IACS) Unified Requirements (UR) E26 and E27. Effective for new build vessels contracted on or after July 1, 2024, these regulations represent the first globally harmonized, mandatory baseline for cybersecurity in shipping.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">1</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While UR E26 addresses the cyber resilience of the vessel as a collective operational entity, UR E27 ("Cyber Resilience of On-Board Systems and Equipment") targets the granular level of the supply chain, placing an unprecedented burden of compliance on equipment manufacturers.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Southeast Asia, a region that functions simultaneously as a global transshipment super-hub, a premier ship repair center, and a burgeoning manufacturing base for marine components, this regulatory shift has triggered a complex industrial reckoning. This report provides an exhaustive analysis of the adoption dynamics of UR E27 among Tier 2 and Tier 3 suppliers across the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN). It dissects a landscape characterized by a "compliance capability gap," where high-maturity suppliers in Singapore are rapidly adapting through government-supported innovation ecosystems, while the fragmented, cost-sensitive supplier bases in Indonesia, Vietnam, and the Philippines struggle with significant technical debt, the prohibitive economics of certification, and a critical shortage of specialized operational technology (OT) cyber-engineering talent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The analysis reveals that the enforcement of these requirements has created an immediate, frantic demand for "cyber-secure by design" components, a demand that the current regional supply chain is ill-equipped to meet. With fewer than 50 systems globally holding full E27 Type Approval as of late 2024, a severe procurement bottleneck has emerged.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">4</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In response, Southeast Asian integrators are increasingly relying on "gateway" architectures—wrapping legacy OT in hardened industrial firewalls—as a primary mechanism of compliance. This strategy, while pragmatic, introduces long-term architectural risks and maintenance burdens that challenge the traditional "fit-and-forget" ethos of maritime engineering. Through a detailed examination of use cases, hurdles, and demand drivers, this report offers a nuanced view of an industry in transition, where the ability to navigate digital certification is rapidly becoming as critical as the ability to weld steel.</span></p>
<h2><strong>1. The Regulatory Architecture: Deconstructing UR E27 for the Component Manufacturer</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To understand the magnitude of the challenge facing Southeast Asian suppliers, one must look beyond the high-level intent of the regulation and examine the granular technical demands it places on the "box builder." UR E27 is not merely a requirement for a password or a firewall; it is a mandate for a Secure Development Lifecycle (SDLC) applied to heavy machinery and embedded electronics. It forces a convergence of traditional marine engineering with advanced IT security practices, a merger for which the regional supply chain is historically unprepared.</span></p>
<h3><strong>1.1 The Scope of Applicability: From Propulsion to Crew Welfare</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">UR E27 applies to "Computer Based Systems" (CBS) categorized under UR E26, which encompasses essential systems such as propulsion, steering, anchoring, and electrical power generation, as well as "important" systems like cargo handling and fire detection.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">1</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The definition of a CBS is expansive, covering any programmable electronic device. This means a Tier 2 supplier in Batam fabricating a main switchboard, or a vendor in Vietnam assembling an alarm monitoring system, must now view their product not just as electrical infrastructure, but as a digital node requiring 30 specific security capabilities.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A critical differentiator in E27 is the distinction between systems connected to trusted versus untrusted networks. Equipment that interfaces with crew welfare networks, business administrative networks, or the public internet—often for remote maintenance or diagnostics—faces a stricter set of 11 additional security controls.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This specifically targets the "connected ship" paradigm, effectively forcing suppliers of IoT-enabled devices to prove their equipment will not serve as a lateral vector for cyberattacks.</span></p>
<p><strong>Table 1: The E27 Capability Matrix and Supplier Implications</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>E27 Requirement Domain</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Technical Mandate for Supplier</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Implications for SE Asian Tier 2/3 Manufacturers</strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Asset Identification</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maintain a dynamic Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) listing all firmware, OS, and libraries.</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Suppliers often use "white label" generic chips from China without tracking firmware versions or vulnerabilities.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Authentication &amp; Access</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Role-Based Access Control (RBAC), MFA for remote access, removal of default passwords.</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Legacy PLCs often have hardcoded "admin/1234" credentials burned into read-only memory, requiring hardware redesign.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">4</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Physical Security</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Port blocking (USB locks), tamper detection, cabinet integrity.</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Requires redesign of physical enclosures (IP56 cabinets) to prevent unauthorized peripheral connection.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">1</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Network Segmentation</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Logical separation of traffic, defined "Zones and Conduits."</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Manufacturers of integrated consoles must now include managed switches and firewalls within the console itself.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">8</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Security Logs</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Continuous logging of user actions and system anomalies (syslog/SNMP).</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Low-cost microcontrollers often lack the storage or processing power to generate and buffer security logs.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">10</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Resilience</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fallback to "Minimal Risk Condition" during a cyber incident.</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Engineering failsafes are standard for mechanical failure, but cyber-induced failure modes (e.g., ransomware on a throttle control) are rarely modeled.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">12</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3><strong>1.2 The "Paperwork Barrier": Documentation as a Barrier to Entry</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For many small engineering firms in the region, the physical engineering of security features is less daunting than the associated documentation burden. UR E27 requires a level of bureaucratic rigor typically associated with aerospace or nuclear industries. Suppliers must submit:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>CBS Asset Inventory:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A granular list of all hardware and software components, including version numbers for third-party libraries.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Topology Diagrams:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Detailed schematics showing logical and physical connections, defining the boundaries of security zones.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">1</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Security Capabilities Description:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A mapping document demonstrating exactly how the device meets the required security capabilities.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Test Procedures:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Validated protocols for testing the cyber resilience of the equipment during Factory Acceptance Tests (FAT) and Sea Acceptance Tests (SAT).</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">13</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Secure Development Lifecycle (SDLC) Evidence:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Proof that security was designed into the product from the concept phase, not retrofitted.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">14</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This documentation requirement disproportionately affects smaller regional suppliers. A global OEM like Wärtsilä or Kongsberg maintains dedicated compliance departments. A medium-sized switchboard manufacturer in Surabaya or a sensor integrator in Manila typically does not, creating a significant barrier to entry for the international newbuild market.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">16</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The cost of producing this documentation, often requiring external consultants, can exceed the profit margin on the hardware itself.</span></p>
<h3><strong>1.3 The Silent Tier: Supply Chain Opacity</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A critical structural weakness in the Southeast Asian adoption curve is the prevalence of the "silent tier"—Tier 3 suppliers who provide PCBs, sensors, actuators, or sub-assemblies to Tier 2 integrators.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">18</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In markets like Vietnam and Indonesia, supply chains are often informal, relying on long-standing relationships rather than digital integration. UR E27 requires visibility into this "silent tier" to track vulnerabilities and ensure software integrity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many Tier 2 integrators in the region are discovering that they cannot certify their systems because their own Tier 3 suppliers—perhaps a local provider of a specific microcontroller board in Ho Chi Minh City or a cable manufacturer in Johor—cannot provide the necessary evidence of secure development or firmware integrity. This "dependency deadlock" creates a situation where the Tier 2 supplier is held responsible for the cyber hygiene of components they do not fully control or understand.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">6</span></p>
<h2><strong>2. Regional Analysis: The Two-Speed Adoption Landscape</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The adoption of UR E27 in Southeast Asia is not a monolithic phenomenon. A distinct bifurcation exists between the advanced maritime hub of Singapore, which operates at the cutting edge of global compliance, and the emerging manufacturing centers of Indonesia, Vietnam, and the Philippines, which face foundational infrastructure and capability gaps.</span></p>
<h3><strong>2.1 Singapore: The Hub of High-Maturity Integration</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Singapore serves as the region's primary node for high-value integration, regulatory compliance, and innovation. The ecosystem here is characterized by strong government support, the presence of major global OEMs, and a highly skilled workforce.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Institutional Support and Funding:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The Maritime and Port Authority of Singapore (MPA) has aggressively pushed for digitalization and cyber resilience through initiatives like the Maritime Innovation and Technology (MINT) Fund and the Maritime Cluster Fund.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">19</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> These grants allow local suppliers to subsidize the high cost of R&amp;D required for E27 compliance. Furthermore, the establishment of the Maritime Cyber Assurance and Operations Centre (MCAOC) provides a centralized mechanism for monitoring and threat intelligence, indirectly supporting suppliers by creating a standardized operating environment.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">21</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Seatrium Effect:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> As one of the world's largest offshore and marine engineering groups, Seatrium (formed from the merger of Sembcorp Marine and Keppel O&amp;M) acts as a powerful enforcement mechanism for E27. Seatrium’s rigorous Supplier Code of Conduct and vendor qualification processes are increasingly aligning with IACS requirements.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">23</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Tier 2 suppliers in Singapore, such as </span><strong>Jason Electronics</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or </span><strong>Pantech Marine Engineering</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">, must meet these standards to remain on the Approved Vendor List (AVL) for major projects.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">25</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Role of Integrators:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Firms like </span><strong>Jason Electronics</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><strong>Cyclect</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (via Applied Automation) serve as vital intermediaries. They do not just distribute hardware; they engineer the "systems of systems" that allow disparate equipment to function securely. Jason Electronics, for example, bridges the gap between global manufacturers (like Cobham or Raytheon) and regional shipyards, ensuring that the "last mile" integration of navigation and communication systems meets Class requirements.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">27</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Their ability to bundle hardware with "managed cyber services" allows them to offer E27 compliance as a value-added service.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>2.2 Indonesia: The Challenge of Retrofitting and Aspirational Standards</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Indonesia’s maritime sector is vast, archipelagic, and heavily reliant on a mix of state-owned enterprises (like PT PAL) and a multitude of smaller private yards in Batam. The adoption of E27 here is complicated by the dual nature of the market: export vs. domestic.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>BKI and the IACS Aspiration:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Biro Klasifikasi Indonesia (BKI) is the national class society. While it strives for full IACS membership and aligns its rules with IACS standards to maintain competitiveness, it is not yet a member.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">29</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> BKI has issued technical circulars regarding cyber resilience that mirror E26/E27 for new constructions.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">31</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This creates a complex environment where suppliers must meet BKI’s "IACS-aligned" rules for domestic builds (Cabotage trade) while meeting actual IACS certification for international export vessels built in Batam (often classed by ABS, DNV, or BV).</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Supplier Struggles:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Indonesian switchboard and automation manufacturers, often local partners of global brands like Terasaki or Schneider, operate on thin margins.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">33</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The requirement to add "smart" capabilities and security hardening to standard electrical switchboards (as seen in the 440V/690V systems) represents a significant R&amp;D burden.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">35</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Local integrators like </span><strong>Arakan Marine Automation</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><strong>PT Sinco Automasi</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> provide essential bridging services, retrofitting cyber-secure capabilities onto legacy hardware, but the depth of "secure by design" engineering remains low among indigenous manufacturers.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">36</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Procurement Gaps:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Procurement processes in Indonesian SOEs (like PT PAL) have historically focused on cost and hardware specifications. Integrating complex cybersecurity criteria (e.g., requiring ISO 27001 or IEC 62443 compliance from vendors) into public procurement is a new and evolving challenge, often leading to delays in tender evaluations as procurement officers struggle to evaluate cyber-compliance.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">38</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>2.3 Vietnam: Manufacturing Capability vs. Cyber Maturity</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vietnam has established itself as a shipbuilding powerhouse, particularly for export vessels (tankers, bulk carriers) via joint ventures like Hyundai Vietnam Shipbuilding (HVS). However, the supplier base faces a steep learning curve.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Hyundai Influence:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Hyundai Vietnam Shipbuilding, as a subsidiary of HD Hyundai, benefits from the parent company's aggressive cyber strategy. HD Hyundai has already secured Approval in Principle (AiP) for cyber resilience from multiple class societies.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">40</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This creates a "compliance umbrella" for the shipyard but puts immense pressure on local Tier 2/3 vendors to meet Korean-standard vendor registration requirements, which now include strict cyber hygiene protocols.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">41</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Legislative Layering:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Vietnam’s adoption of UR E27 is complicated by its own stringent domestic cybersecurity laws—specifically the Law on Cybersecurity (2018) and the upcoming 2025/2026 revisions.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">42</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> These laws impose data localization and system classification requirements (Level 1 to 5) that overlap with, and sometimes contradict, IACS data handling requirements. Vietnamese suppliers must navigate this dual compliance regime, ensuring their products satisfy both Class surveyors (for the ship’s safety) and the Ministry of Public Security (for national data sovereignty).</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Supplier Base:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Vietnam’s supplier base includes companies like </span><strong>Hai Nam Automation</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and numerous providers of steel and electrical components.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">44</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While strong in electrical engineering, the transition to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">cyber-secure</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> engineering is in its infancy. Many rely on distributing global brands (Siemens, Schneider) rather than developing indigenous secure logic controllers, reducing the E27 burden to one of configuration rather than product development. However, firms like </span><strong>Techno-Trade</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are beginning to introduce automation solutions that bridge this gap.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">46</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>2.4 Philippines: The Manning Focus and Software Potential</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Philippines occupies a unique niche. While it is the world's fourth-largest shipbuilding nation (dominated by Hanjin's legacy and Tsuneishi), its indigenous equipment manufacturing base is smaller compared to Vietnam or Indonesia. The focus here is heavily skewed toward the human element.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Cyber Hygiene Training:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The Philippines is the primary supplier of global maritime labor. Consequently, the adoption of cyber standards here manifests largely in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">training</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> rather than manufacturing. Institutions like the Maritime Industry Authority (MARINA) focus on integrating cyber hygiene into seafarer curriculum to meet IMO and IACS operational requirements.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">47</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Software and Outsourcing:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> There is a growing sector of software development and IT outsourcing in the Philippines servicing the maritime sector. These firms are increasingly tasked with developing the "crew welfare" apps and "ship management" software that run on the vessel's IT networks. For these Tier 3 software suppliers, E27 compliance means adopting secure coding practices and rigorous vulnerability testing.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">49</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>3. Hurdles and Struggles: The Supplier's Dilemma</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The transition to UR E27 compliance is creating existential struggles for Tier 2 and 3 suppliers across the region. The hurdles are financial, technical, and human.</span></p>
<h3><strong>3.1 The "Type Approval" Bottleneck and Cost</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most immediate hurdle is the scarcity of E27 Type Approved equipment. As of late 2024, reports suggest fewer than 30-50 major systems globally had achieved full certification.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">4</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> For a Southeast Asian shipyard, this restricts the Approved Vendor List (AVL) dramatically.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Cost Prohibitions:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Obtaining Type Approval from a major class society (DNV, ABS, ClassNK) involves rigorous testing, documentation review, and often the hiring of external cyber consultants. For a small manufacturer of bilge alarm systems in Vietnam or Indonesia, this cost is disproportionate to the unit price of their equipment.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">17</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Recurring Costs:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Unlike a one-off hardware certification, cyber resilience requires ongoing maintenance (patch management, vulnerability monitoring). This shifts the business model from "install and forget" to "lifecycle support," a service model many Tier 3 suppliers are not structured to provide financially or operationally.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">5</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>3.2 The Technical Debt of Legacy OT</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A significant portion of the maritime supply chain in Southeast Asia involves the retrofit or continued production of legacy designs—pumps, winches, and engine controls that have functioned reliably for decades without connectivity.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Connectivity Paradox:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> To achieve the "smart ship" status required by modern buyers, these mechanical systems are being fitted with sensors and connected to shipboard networks. However, the underlying controllers (PLCs) often lack the processing power to support encryption, user logging, or modern authentication protocols required by E27.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">7</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Protocol Insecurity:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Many legacy systems utilize industrial protocols like Modbus RTU or NMEA 0183, which were designed without security in mind (no encryption, no authentication). Securing these protocols to meet E27 standards (which requires protection against unauthorized access and data manipulation) is technically impossible at the protocol level, forcing suppliers to use encapsulation or gateway strategies.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">50</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>3.3 The Talent Vacuum</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is a profound shortage of engineering talent in Southeast Asia that possesses dual competency in Marine Engineering and Operational Technology (OT) Cybersecurity.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Misaligned Skills:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Electrical engineers in regional shipyards are expert in power distribution and heavy machinery but often lack training in network segmentation, firewalls, and secure coding practices demanded by IEC 62443 (the standard underpinning E27).</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">51</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Training Deficits:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While Singapore has launched initiatives like the MariOT testbed and training courses with Singapore Polytechnic </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">22</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, such resources are scarce in Indonesia and Vietnam. Suppliers in these countries often rely on generic IT security training which does not address the specific constraints of maritime OT (e.g., safety-critical latency, non-standard protocols).</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">51</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>4. Use Cases and Technical Adoption Strategies</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite these hurdles, adoption is occurring, driven by necessity. Suppliers are employing specific technical and architectural strategies to meet E27 requirements.</span></p>
<h3><strong>4.1 Use Case A: The "Secure Gateway" Enclave</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most prevalent use case for UR E27 adoption among Tier 2 suppliers is the deployment of </span><strong>Maritime Cyber Gateways</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Since redesigning a windlass control system to support encryption is capital-intensive and time-consuming, suppliers are placing a secure gateway between their equipment and the vessel's OT network.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Technology:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Companies are utilizing hardened industrial routers from vendors like </span><strong>Moxa</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (EDR series), </span><strong>Robustel</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (MG460 series), and </span><strong>Fortinet</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. These devices are specifically marketed as "IEC 61162-460 / UR E27 aligned".</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">8</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Implementation:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A Vietnamese switchboard manufacturer (Tier 2) uses a standard PLC (Tier 3) for generator control. To meet E27, they install a Moxa EDR-810 firewall in the switchboard cabinet. The firewall handles the E27 requirements for "Network Segmentation" and "Access Control," effectively shielding the "dumb" PLC from the ship's network. It creates a "secure enclave" where the legacy device can operate safely.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Regional Relevance:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is particularly popular in the retrofit market in Singapore and Malaysia, where existing vessels are being upgraded to "Cyber Secure" class notations without ripping out functioning machinery. Distributors like </span><strong>Alvasta</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Indonesia), </span><strong>ElectGo</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Indonesia), and </span><strong>Assured Systems</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are key enablers of this trend, supplying the hardware that allows legacy mechanical firms to claim compliance.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">11</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>4.2 Use Case B: Managed Cyber Services for Connectivity</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For navigation and communication suppliers (Tier 2), adoption has moved beyond hardware to managed services. This sector faces the highest scrutiny because it sits at the interface between the ship and the outside world (the "untrusted network").</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Cobham/Thrane &amp; Thrane:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The SAILOR 900 VSAT series, widely distributed by </span><strong>AMI Marine</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Vietnam and </span><strong>Jason Electronics</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Singapore, integrates cybersecurity features directly into the terminal's Below Deck Unit (BDU).</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">57</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Service Wrap:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Suppliers are no longer just selling an antenna; they are selling a "Cyber Secure Connectivity" package. This includes managed firewalls, intrusion detection systems (IDS), and continuous logging—features that satisfy E27's requirement for "Detect" and "Respond" capabilities.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">59</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Benefit:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This relieves the shipowner of the burden of configuring the device, shifting the compliance risk to the supplier (e.g., Inmarsat Fleet Xpress or KVH Managed Firewall).</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This model is gaining traction among smaller vessel operators (tugs and barges) who lack onboard IT staff.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>4.3 Use Case C: Digital Twin and Virtual Commissioning</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In advanced shipyards (like Seatrium or HD Hyundai's Vietnam operations), virtual commissioning is emerging as a high-end use case for E27 compliance.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Mechanism:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Before physical installation, the ship's network topology is modeled digitally. Suppliers must provide digital models or "twins" of their components to verify network segmentation and access controls.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Adoption:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is currently limited to top-tier suppliers who can provide such digital assets. It allows the shipyard to validate the "Zones and Conduits" diagram required by Class before steel is cut, reducing the risk of costly rework during the commissioning phase.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Singapore's MariOT testbed at SUTD is a prime example of infrastructure supporting this sophisticated validation.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">53</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>5. Demand Drivers and Procurement Dynamics</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Demand for E27 compliance in Southeast Asia is not organic; it is a top-down imposition driven by three distinct and powerful forces.</span></p>
<h3><strong>5.1 The "Class Notation" Cascade</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shipowners, particularly those chartering to energy majors (Shell, ExxonMobil, Petronas), require vessels to have specific Class Notations (e.g., DNV's </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Secure (Essential)</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or ABS's </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Safety</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">).</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Impact:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Since July 1, 2024, these notations mandate E26/E27 compliance.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">2</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A supplier in Surabaya cannot sell a main switchboard to a DNV-classed tanker project without providing the E27 evidence dossier (topology, security capabilities, test procedures).</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">13</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Verification:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Classification societies (ClassNK, DNV, ABS) act as the gatekeepers. Their surveyors are now asking for evidence of "hardening" (disabled USB ports, password policies) during Factory Acceptance Tests (FAT), forcing suppliers to upgrade their testing protocols.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">14</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>5.2 National Security and Critical Infrastructure Laws</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Singapore:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The Cybersecurity Act designates maritime infrastructure as Critical Information Infrastructure (CII). This compels port operators (PSA) and major maritime firms to enforce strict supply chain cyber hygiene, cascading requirements down to maintenance contractors.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">22</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Vietnam:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The new Law on Cybersecurity (effective 2025/2026) classifies information systems by security level. Level 3 systems (critical national infrastructure) face strict audit and import license requirements for cyber-products. This forces Vietnamese suppliers to ensure their imported components (e.g., from China or Europe) meet these new national standards alongside IACS rules.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">43</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>5.3 Energy Major Vetting (TMSA 3 / SIRE 2.0)</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Tanker Management and Self Assessment (TMSA) and the new SIRE 2.0 inspection regimes heavily weigh cyber resilience. Ship operators know that non-compliant equipment can lead to vetting failures, which means the vessel cannot be chartered. Consequently, procurement departments are rewriting vendor contracts to include indemnification clauses regarding cyber incidents, effectively forcing Tier 2 suppliers to carry cyber liability insurance or prove robust E27 compliance.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">2</span></p>
<h2><strong>6. Open Questions and Future Outlook</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the deadline passing, the industry remains in a state of flux. Several critical questions and trends will define the next 24 months.</span></p>
<h3><strong>6.1 The "Validation Void": Who audits the Tier 3s?</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An open question remains regarding the depth of auditing. While Class societies review the Tier 2 integrator, they rarely have the resources to audit the Tier 3 component maker in a remote industrial park in Shenzhen or Cikarang. Will the industry accept self-declarations from these sub-suppliers, or will a new market for "Cyber Verification Agents" emerge? The reliance on paper-based compliance creates a risk of "paper security" without actual technical resilience.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">6</span></p>
<h3><strong>6.2 The Cost of Obsolescence and the "Grey Market"</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What happens to the massive inventory of non-compliant spare parts sitting in warehouses across Singapore and Busan? Can a non-E27 spare part be installed on an E27-certified vessel during a repair? The regulatory guidance on "maintenance of class" suggests no, but operational reality may dictate otherwise. This creates the potential for a "grey market" of non-compliant spares, posing a significant threat to the integrity of certified vessels.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">14</span></p>
<h3><strong>6.3 Convergence or Divergence?</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will Southeast Asia converge on the IACS standard, or will national interests fracture the market? Vietnam's specific data localization and cyber-product licensing laws suggest a potential divergence, where a "Vietnam-compliant" ship might differ slightly from a "Singapore-compliant" one. This would complicate life for regional suppliers who export to multiple markets, potentially requiring different product SKUs for different jurisdictions.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">65</span></p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The adoption of IACS UR E27 in Southeast Asia is a story of asymmetric progress. Singaporean integrators and global OEMs are racing ahead, leveraging advanced gateways and managed services to monetize compliance. They are turning a regulatory burden into a competitive advantage. In contrast, the broader base of Tier 2 and Tier 3 suppliers in Indonesia and Vietnam faces a steep climb, burdened by the need to digitize and secure mechanical legacies with limited resources and talent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the supplier, the message is clear: E27 is not just a technical specification; it is a market access license. Those who can wrap their products in verified security—whether through native engineering or smart gateway integration—will dominate the Authorized Vendor Lists of the future. Those who cannot will be relegated to the shrinking market of non-IACS, domestic-only tonnage. As the "silent tier" becomes a source of noisy risk, the maritime industry in Southeast Asia enters a period of rigorous, and painful, maturation.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Table 2: Comparative Adoption Readiness in Southeast Asia</strong></h3>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Country</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Primary Driver</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Supplier Readiness Level</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Key Hurdle</strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Singapore</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MPA Policy, Global Hub Status</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>High</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Tier 1/2)</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cost of compliance for SMEs; Talent shortage.</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Vietnam</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hyundai JV, National Cyber Law</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Medium</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Export) / </span><strong>Low</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Domestic)</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overlap of IACS &amp; National Law; Reliance on component imports.</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Indonesia</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BKI Standards, Domestic Cabotage</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Low</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to </span><strong>Medium</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lack of Type Approved domestic products; Funding for R&amp;D.</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Malaysia</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oil &amp; Gas (Petronas) Standards</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Medium</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Transitioning legacy offshore support vessels to new standards.</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Philippines</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crewing/Manning focus</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Low</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Manufacturing)</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Focus is on training crew (cyber hygiene) rather than manufacturing equipment.</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sources: </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">43</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IACS UR E27 Rev.1 - Hull Classification Surveys, </span><a href="https://www.classnk.or.jp/hp/pdf/info_service/iacs_ur_and_ui/ur_e27_rev.1_sep_2023_cln.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.classnk.or.jp/hp/pdf/info_service/iacs_ur_and_ui/ur_e27_rev.1_sep_2023_cln.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IACS unified requirements for cyber security mandatory from 1 ..., </span><a href="https://www.dnv.com/news/2022/iacs-unified-requirements-for-cyber-security-mandatory-from-1-january-2024-227429/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.dnv.com/news/2022/iacs-unified-requirements-for-cyber-security-mandatory-from-1-january-2024-227429/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IACS unified requirements E26 and E27 Cyber security beyond ..., </span><a href="https://www.inmarsat.com/content/dam/viasat-maritime/perspectives/documents/MBU_IACS_UR_E26_E27_whitepaper_June_2024.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.inmarsat.com/content/dam/viasat-maritime/perspectives/documents/MBU_IACS_UR_E26_E27_whitepaper_June_2024.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IACS UR E26-E27 Implementation for VLCC Cyber Resilience, </span><a href="https://medium.com/@shipsec.guardian/iacs-ur-e26-e27-implementation-for-vlcc-cyber-resilience-ef386d9d520f"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://medium.com/@shipsec.guardian/iacs-ur-e26-e27-implementation-for-vlcc-cyber-resilience-ef386d9d520f</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">New Mandatory cyber-security requirements coming in July 2024, </span><a href="https://marine-safety-consultant.ch/new-mandatory-cyber-security-requirements-coming-in-july-2024/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://marine-safety-consultant.ch/new-mandatory-cyber-security-requirements-coming-in-july-2024/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why IACS UR E26 Falls Short of True Maritime Cyber Resilience, </span><a href="https://medium.com/@shipsec.guardian/why-iacs-ur-e26-falls-short-of-true-maritime-cyber-resilience-33389da1ae6b"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://medium.com/@shipsec.guardian/why-iacs-ur-e26-falls-short-of-true-maritime-cyber-resilience-33389da1ae6b</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity IACS E26 and E27 - Speedcast, </span><a href="https://www.speedcast.com/blog-hub/2025/iacs-e26-e27-standards/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.speedcast.com/blog-hub/2025/iacs-e26-e27-standards/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maritime Networking &amp; Cybersecurity | IACS E26/E27 - Robustel, </span><a href="https://robustel.com/products/maritime-networking-cybersecurity/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://robustel.com/products/maritime-networking-cybersecurity/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maritime IoT and cyber security solutions - Robustel, </span><a href="https://robustel.com/solutions/maritime/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://robustel.com/solutions/maritime/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity Challenges in The Maritime Industry | PDF - Scribd, </span><a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/807970657/Cybersecurity-Challenges-in-the-Maritime-Industry"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.scribd.com/document/807970657/Cybersecurity-Challenges-in-the-Maritime-Industry</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">MG360 | Official Robustel Distributor and Integrator - Assured Systems, </span><a href="https://www.assured-systems.com/robustel-mg360-maritime-cyber-security-gateway/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.assured-systems.com/robustel-mg360-maritime-cyber-security-gateway/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recommendation on Cyber Resilience No. 166 - Steamship Mutual, </span><a href="https://www.steamshipmutual.com/sites/default/files/downloads/articles/2020/IACS-Recommendation-on-Cyber-resilience-No-166-2020_04.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.steamshipmutual.com/sites/default/files/downloads/articles/2020/IACS-Recommendation-on-Cyber-resilience-No-166-2020_04.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TYPE APPROVAL CERTIFICATE - Zenitel, </span><a href="https://www.zenitel.com/sites/default/files/2025-10/DNV%20Cyber%20%28SP1%29%20-%20IACS%20UR%20E27%20-%202027-06-24%20-%20TAA00003MY.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.zenitel.com/sites/default/files/2025-10/DNV%20Cyber%20%28SP1%29%20-%20IACS%20UR%20E27%20-%202027-06-24%20-%20TAA00003MY.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IACS UR E27 Cybersecurity Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs), </span><a href="https://ww2.eagle.org/en/Products-and-Services/vendor-certification/abs-cybersafety-for-resilience/faq-cyber-resilience-program.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://ww2.eagle.org/en/Products-and-Services/vendor-certification/abs-cybersafety-for-resilience/faq-cyber-resilience-program.html</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TYPE APPROVAL CERTIFICATE - Bachmann.info, </span><a href="https://www.bachmann.info/media/5671/download/Bachmann_DNV_MC_MH_MX_series_en_2024.pdf?v=1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.bachmann.info/media/5671/download/Bachmann_DNV_MC_MH_MX_series_en_2024.pdf?v=1</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Security: Supply Chain Risk Management and Defense-in ..., </span><a href="https://library.imarest.org/record/7692/files/INEC_2020_Paper_80.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://library.imarest.org/record/7692/files/INEC_2020_Paper_80.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">From zero to hero - IACS UR E26 &amp; E27 mandatory cyber regulations, </span><a href="https://www.port-it.nl/latest-news/from-zero-to-hero/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.port-it.nl/latest-news/from-zero-to-hero/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why Tier-2 and Tier-3 Suppliers Hold the Future of Supply Chain ..., </span><a href="https://ean-network.com/the-power-of-the-silent-tier-why-tier-2-and-tier-3-suppliers-hold-the-future-of-supply-chain-stability/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://ean-network.com/the-power-of-the-silent-tier-why-tier-2-and-tier-3-suppliers-hold-the-future-of-supply-chain-stability/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">MINT Fund | Maritime &amp; Port Authority of Singapore (MPA), </span><a href="https://www.mpa.gov.sg/maritime-singapore/what-maritime-singapore-offers/programmes-to-support-your-maritime-business/mint-fund"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.mpa.gov.sg/maritime-singapore/what-maritime-singapore-offers/programmes-to-support-your-maritime-business/mint-fund</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Grants and Funding | Maritime &amp; Port Authority of Singapore (MPA), </span><a href="https://www.mpa.gov.sg/maritime-singapore/what-maritime-singapore-offers/programmes-to-support-your-maritime-business"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.mpa.gov.sg/maritime-singapore/what-maritime-singapore-offers/programmes-to-support-your-maritime-business</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Details - Maritime &amp; Port Authority of Singapore (MPA), </span><a href="https://www.mpa.gov.sg/media-centre/details/driving-growth-and-innovation-to-strengthen-maritime-competitiveness-and-resilence"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.mpa.gov.sg/media-centre/details/driving-growth-and-innovation-to-strengthen-maritime-competitiveness-and-resilence</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Singapore's MPA launches Maritime Cybersecurity Operations Centre, </span><a href="https://www.rivieramm.com/news-content-hub/news-content-hub/singapores-mpa-launches-maritime-cybersecurity-operations-centre-54661"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.rivieramm.com/news-content-hub/news-content-hub/singapores-mpa-launches-maritime-cybersecurity-operations-centre-54661</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Supplier Code of Conduct - Seatrium, </span><a href="https://www.seatrium.com/assets/reports/851.5-FRM1-Supplier_Code_of_Conduct_Seatrium.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.seatrium.com/assets/reports/851.5-FRM1-Supplier_Code_of_Conduct_Seatrium.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Compliance Business Code of Conduct - Seatrium, </span><a href="https://www.seatrium.com/assets/code-of-conduct/Seatrium-Business-Code-of-Conduct.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.seatrium.com/assets/code-of-conduct/Seatrium-Business-Code-of-Conduct.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brochures | Jason Marine Group, </span><a href="https://www.jason.com.sg/brochures"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.jason.com.sg/brochures</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Contact - Pantech Group, </span><a href="https://pantech-group.com/contact/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://pantech-group.com/contact/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">jason electronics (pte) ltd - Asia Marine &amp; Offshore Industries Directory, </span><a href="https://www.sgmarineindustries.com/company-details/jason-electronics-pte-ltd/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.sgmarineindustries.com/company-details/jason-electronics-pte-ltd/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jason - ShipServ, </span><a href="https://www.shipserv.com/ShipServ/pages/profiles/53945/documents/Jason-Electronics-Brochure.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.shipserv.com/ShipServ/pages/profiles/53945/documents/Jason-Electronics-Brochure.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Biro Klasifikasi Indonesia - Maritime Directory, </span><a href="https://directory.marinelink.com/companies/company/biro-klasifikasi-indonesia-209442"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://directory.marinelink.com/companies/company/biro-klasifikasi-indonesia-209442</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">BKI - Rules For Classification and Construction - Vol.1 2022 | PDF, </span><a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/666528910/BKI-Rules-For-Classification-And-Construction-Part-1-Seagoing-Ships-Vol-1-2022"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.scribd.com/document/666528910/BKI-Rules-For-Classification-And-Construction-Part-1-Seagoing-Ships-Vol-1-2022</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Latest Trends in Ship Cybersecurity Regulations - ClassNK, </span><a href="https://www.classnk.or.jp/hp/pdf/research/rd/2024/10_e06.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.classnk.or.jp/hp/pdf/research/rd/2024/10_e06.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">PT. Biro Klasifikasi Indonesia (BKI) - IKA PPNS, </span><a href="https://ika.ppns.ac.id/pt-biro-klasifikasi-indonesia-bki/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://ika.ppns.ac.id/pt-biro-klasifikasi-indonesia-bki/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Global Network｜ABOUT TERASAKI｜TERASAKI ELECTRIC CO.,LTD, </span><a href="https://www.terasaki.co.jp/english/about/offices.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.terasaki.co.jp/english/about/offices.html</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jual TERASAKI ELECTRIC oleh PT. TOTAL ABADI SOLUSINDO, </span><a href="https://totalabadi.indonetwork.co.id/products/terasaki-electric-546509"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://totalabadi.indonetwork.co.id/products/terasaki-electric-546509</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">440V/690V Low-Voltage Marine Switchboard | manufacturer &amp; price, </span><a href="https://www.smartelecmfg.com/Switchgear/product/440v-690v-low-voltage-marine-switchboard/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.smartelecmfg.com/Switchgear/product/440v-690v-low-voltage-marine-switchboard/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Arakanmarine | Marine Automation, </span><a href="https://arakanmarine.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://arakanmarine.com/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">introduction - Sinco Marine, </span><a href="https://www.sincomarine.com/doc/COMPANY-PROFILE_SINCO_MARINE_SOLUTION_compressed.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.sincomarine.com/doc/COMPANY-PROFILE_SINCO_MARINE_SOLUTION_compressed.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity Considerations for Procurement Process, </span><a href="https://www.energy.gov/femp/articles/cybersecurity-considerations-procurement-process"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.energy.gov/femp/articles/cybersecurity-considerations-procurement-process</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prevention of Corruption in the Procurement of Goods/Services ..., </span><a href="https://www.ajhssr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/M2590999106.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.ajhssr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/M2590999106.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HD Hyundai gets global ship cyber security certifications - KED Global, </span><a href="https://www.kedglobal.com/shipping-shipbuilding/newsView/ked202406250008"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.kedglobal.com/shipping-shipbuilding/newsView/ked202406250008</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HD Hyundai in ship cyber security tie-up - Lloyd's List, </span><a href="https://www.lloydslist.com/LL1148011/HD-Hyundai-in-ship-cyber-security-tie-up"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.lloydslist.com/LL1148011/HD-Hyundai-in-ship-cyber-security-tie-up</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vietnam's Law on Cybersecurity 2025: What's New and What ..., </span><a href="https://www.frasersvn.com/legal-updates-and-publications/vietnam-s-law-on-cybersecurity-2025-what-s-new-and-what-businesses-need-to-know"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.frasersvn.com/legal-updates-and-publications/vietnam-s-law-on-cybersecurity-2025-what-s-new-and-what-businesses-need-to-know</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vietnam's New Cybersecurity Law to Take Effect January 2026 - DFDL, </span><a href="https://www.dfdl.com/insights/legal-and-tax-updates/vietnams-new-cybersecurity-law-to-take-effect-january-2026/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.dfdl.com/insights/legal-and-tax-updates/vietnams-new-cybersecurity-law-to-take-effect-january-2026/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hai Nam Automation Technology JSC.: Home, </span><a href="https://www.hainamsi.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.hainamsi.com/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Round Steel Pipe (galvanized, non galvanized), </span><a href="https://investvietnam.vn/round-steel-pipe-galvanized-non-galvanized2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://investvietnam.vn/round-steel-pipe-galvanized-non-galvanized2</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technotrade LLC, </span><a href="https://www.technotrade.ua/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.technotrade.ua/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Philippine Maritime Industry, </span><a href="https://marina.gov.ph/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/OSS-Newsletter-Volume-2-July-2019.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://marina.gov.ph/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/OSS-Newsletter-Volume-2-July-2019.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">MIDP 2028 - MARITIME INDUSTRY AUTHORITY, </span><a href="https://marina.gov.ph/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/MIDP-2028-as-of-29-April-2024.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://marina.gov.ph/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/MIDP-2028-as-of-29-April-2024.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improving Maritime Cybersecurity in Southeast Asia: Suggestions for ..., </span><a href="https://brill.com/view/journals/apoc/8/2/article-p329_008.xml"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://brill.com/view/journals/apoc/8/2/article-p329_008.xml</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secure Remote Access to Legacy Equipment on Closed Networks, </span><a href="https://www.remote.it/resources/remote-access-legacy-equipment-closed-networks"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.remote.it/resources/remote-access-legacy-equipment-closed-networks</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Challenges in Maritime Cybersecurity Training and Compliance, </span><a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2077-1312/12/10/1844"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.mdpi.com/2077-1312/12/10/1844</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The impact of IACS UR E26, UR E27 - Theseus, </span><a href="https://www.theseus.fi/bitstream/10024/895631/2/Ungureanu_Alexandra.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.theseus.fi/bitstream/10024/895631/2/Ungureanu_Alexandra.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collective Efforts to Strengthen Maritime Cybersecurity, </span><a href="https://www.mpa.gov.sg/media-centre/details/collective-efforts-to-strengthen-maritime-cybersecurity"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.mpa.gov.sg/media-centre/details/collective-efforts-to-strengthen-maritime-cybersecurity</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Holistic Smart Maritime Solutions for Cyber-resilience - Moxa, </span><a href="https://www.moxa.com/en/spotlight/integrated-solutions/marine/maritime-solutions-for-cyber-resilience/index"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.moxa.com/en/spotlight/integrated-solutions/marine/maritime-solutions-for-cyber-resilience/index</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moxa Distributor di Indonesia - Electgo, </span><a href="https://electgo.id/brands/moxa"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://electgo.id/brands/moxa</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moxa Solusi Jaringan Industri 4.0 - alvasta-tech.com, </span><a href="https://www.alvasta-tech.com/moxa"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.alvasta-tech.com/moxa</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cobham SAILOR 900 VSAT Ka Maritime Satellite Internet System ..., </span><a href="https://www.asiasatellite.co/Cobham-SAILOR-900-Ka-VSAT-System-p/Cobham-SAILOR-900-Ka-VSAT-System.htm"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.asiasatellite.co/Cobham-SAILOR-900-Ka-VSAT-System-p/Cobham-SAILOR-900-Ka-VSAT-System.htm</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cobham Satcom - AMI Marine Vietnam, </span><a href="https://www.amisales.com.vn/cobham-satcom?___store=vietnam"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.amisales.com.vn/cobham-satcom?___store=vietnam</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity &amp; Managed Firewall - KVH Integrated Hardware, </span><a href="https://www.kvh.com/managed-services/fleet-services/managed-firewall/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.kvh.com/managed-services/fleet-services/managed-firewall/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Overview - GTMaritime, </span><a href="https://www.gtmaritime.com/services/cyber-overview/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.gtmaritime.com/services/cyber-overview/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inmarsat Fleet One Plans | Maritime Voice &amp; Data Costs, </span><a href="https://satellitephonestore.com/service-plans/fleet-one-service-plans"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://satellitephonestore.com/service-plans/fleet-one-service-plans</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber security approval of components and systems - DNV, </span><a href="https://www.dnv.com/services/cyber-security-approval-of-components-and-systems-124196/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.dnv.com/services/cyber-security-approval-of-components-and-systems-124196/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber-Attacks as an Evolving Threat to Southeast Asia's Maritime ..., </span><a href="https://amti.csis.org/cyber-attacks-as-an-evolving-threat-to-southeast-asias-maritime-security/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://amti.csis.org/cyber-attacks-as-an-evolving-threat-to-southeast-asias-maritime-security/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Secure class notation - DNV, </span><a href="https://www.dnv.com/services/cyber-secure-class-notation-124600/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.dnv.com/services/cyber-secure-class-notation-124600/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vietnam's Draft Cybersecurity Law 2025 – Key Changes Businesses ..., </span><a href="https://rouse.com/insights/news/2025/vietnam-s-draft-cybersecurity-law-2025-key-changes-businesses-need-to-know"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://rouse.com/insights/news/2025/vietnam-s-draft-cybersecurity-law-2025-key-changes-businesses-need-to-know</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Security and Cyber Information Safety Regulations in Vietnam, </span><a href="https://vci-legal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Cyber-Security-Law-in-Vietnam.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://vci-legal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Cyber-Security-Law-in-Vietnam.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regional freight transport infrastructure and policy in Southeast Asia, </span><a href="https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/regional_freight_transport_infrastructure_and_policy_in_southeast_asia.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/regional_freight_transport_infrastructure_and_policy_in_southeast_asia.pdf</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">About Us | IPERINDO - WordPress.com, </span><a href="https://dppiperindo.wordpress.com/about/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://dppiperindo.wordpress.com/about/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Singapore Norway Maritime Cyber Forum - NBAS, </span><a href="https://nbas.org.sg/news/singapore-norway-maritime-cyber-forum/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://nbas.org.sg/news/singapore-norway-maritime-cyber-forum/</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IACS PROCEDURES, </span><a href="https://www.ccs.org.cn/ccswz/file/download?fileid=201900004000000903"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.ccs.org.cn/ccswz/file/download?fileid=201900004000000903</span></a></li>
</ol>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Navigating IACS UR E26 and E27</title>
        <author>
            <name>e27 team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ure27.com/post-3.html"/>
        <id>https://ure27.com/post-3.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://ure27.com/media/posts/8/Gemini_Generated_Image_rp75l1rp75l1rp75.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="HowTo"/>
            <category term="E27"/>

        <updated>2025-12-29T15:58:39+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://ure27.com/media/posts/8/Gemini_Generated_Image_rp75l1rp75l1rp75.png" alt="" />
                    Maritime Cyber Resilience: Navigating IACS UR E26 and E27 A Strategic Guide&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://ure27.com/media/posts/8/Gemini_Generated_Image_rp75l1rp75l1rp75.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <h1><strong>Maritime Cyber Resilience: Navigating IACS UR E26 and E27</strong></h1>
<p><strong>A Strategic Guide for Tier 2 and Tier 3 Suppliers</strong></p>
<h2><strong>1. The Shifting Market Landscape: Cybersecurity as a New Business Requirement</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>1.1 The July 1, 2024 Milestone</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For decades, maritime equipment standards focused primarily on physical safety and environmental performance</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, the digitization of vessel operations has introduced a new dimension of risk</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On July 1, 2024, the industry crossed a critical regulatory threshold: the International Association of Classification Societies (IACS) Unified Requirements (UR) E26 and E27 officially entered into force for new vessel construction contracts</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This milestone represents a fundamental shift from voluntary guidelines to mandatory classification rules</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. While equipment for existing vessels may continue under previous standards, the market for new tonnage has effectively changed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>The New Baseline:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Cyber resilience is no longer an optional "value-add" for premium vessels; it is now a minimum condition for classification for essential onboard systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. As fleets renew, non-compliant equipment will increasingly be viewed as a liability</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Shipowners and operators are beginning to demand cyber-resilient systems to ensure asset protection and continuity of operations, regardless of specific contract dates</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>1.2 The Shipyard's Perspective</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To understand the pressure on suppliers, one must look at the shipyard's new responsibilities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Under UR E26, the shipyard (acting as the Systems Integrator) is now responsible for the cyber resilience of the entire vessel</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. They must demonstrate to the Classification Society that the ship's network is segmented, secure, and monitored</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The shipyard cannot achieve this vessel-level compliance if the individual components—the "bricks" that make up the ship—are insecure. Consequently, shipyards are pushing liability down the supply chain</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. They are increasingly requiring Tier 2 and Tier 3 suppliers to provide:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Transparent Documentation:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Shipyards need detailed asset inventories and topology diagrams to design their security zones</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Integration Readiness:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Suppliers who cannot define their digital interfaces or firewall requirements create a "dependency deadlock," preventing the shipyard from finalizing the vessel design</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the shipyard, a supplier without E27 documentation represents a project risk that can delay commissioning and delivery</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. As a result, procurement departments are rewriting vendor contracts to mandate E27 compliance as a prerequisite for remaining on the Approved Vendor List (AVL)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>1.3 Reducing Commercial Friction</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this new regulatory environment, having "Cyber Ready" products is a strategic advantage that reduces friction during the sales and delivery process</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Simplifying Acceptance:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Systems that hold a valid </span><strong>Type Approval</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (a pre-certification confirming a product meets Class requirements) for UR E27 allow for a significantly streamlined approval process</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. For Type Approved equipment, the shipyard and shipowner are spared from witnessing extensive cybersecurity tests for that specific component, reducing the documentation burden for every individual ship project</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Avoiding Delays:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Non-compliant documentation is a leading cause of technical queries and delays during the commissioning phase</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">20</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Providing a pre-certified, E27-compliant system positions a supplier as a low-risk partner</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Competitive Differentiation:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> As the industry scrambles to adapt, suppliers who can offer "plug-and-play" compliance will likely capture market share from competitors who treat cybersecurity as an afterthough</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. By proactively aligning with these requirements, suppliers move from being a potential compliance bottleneck to an essential partner in the delivery of cyber-resilient vessels</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">23</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2><strong>2. Does This Apply to My Product? (Scope &amp; Definitions)</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Tier 2 and Tier 3 suppliers, the most immediate challenge is determining whether a specific component or sub-system falls under the regulatory umbrella of IACS UR E27</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">24</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The scope is deliberately broad, moving beyond traditional "IT" equipment to encompass the vast majority of </span><strong>Operational Technology (OT)</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">—the hardware and software that detects or causes changes in physical processes—found on modern vessels</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>2.1 Defining a "Computer Based System" (CBS)</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Executive leadership often assumes cybersecurity regulations apply only to servers, workstations, or complex bridge systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, UR E27 applies to any </span><strong>Computer Based System (CBS)</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>The Regulatory Definition:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A CBS is defined not by its interface but by its underlying technology</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If your product is a "programmable electronic device" or a set of such devices that processes, stores, or transmits information, it is a CBS</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">29</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>In Practical Terms:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If your equipment contains a microchip, firmware, or software, it is likely in scope</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This includes:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Programmable Logic Controllers (PLCs):</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Even basic controllers used for auxiliary machinery</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Embedded Devices:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Sensors, actuators, or alarm panels running embedded firmware</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Network Equipment:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Managed switches, routers, and gateways</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Human-Machine Interfaces (HMIs):</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Touchscreens and display panels used for monitoring or control</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The "Black Box" Rule:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You can no longer supply a "black box" without disclosing its digital composition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You must be prepared to list every software component (including Operating System and firmware versions) in a CBS Asset Inventory</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>2.2 The "Air-Gap" Reality</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A common misconception among manufacturers is the belief that "my system is not connected to the ship's network or the internet, so this does not apply to me"</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Under UR E27, being "offline" or </span><strong>"air-gapped"</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (physically isolated from other networks) does not automatically grant an exemption</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>The Physical Interface Risk:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The regulation recognizes that cyber incidents often originate from physical access, not just network intrusions</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If your "isolated" system has a physical port—such as a USB port, Service Port, or Serial Port—used for maintenance, updates, or diagnostics, it is considered vulnerable</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>Exclusion is Difficult:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> To be legally excluded from UR E27, a system must meet a strict set of criteria verified by a Risk Assessment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The system must:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have zero IP-network connections to other systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have no accessible physical interface ports (e.g., USB ports must be permanently disabled or blocked)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be located in a physically controlled access area</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not be an integrated control system</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If a service technician ever needs to plug a laptop into your device to troubleshoot it, your device effectively fails the "isolation" test and must likely comply with E27 requirements</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>2.3 Essential vs. Non-Critical Systems</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The stringency of the requirements depends on the function your system performs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">47</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. UR E27 targets systems where failure could endanger the ship, human safety, or the environment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>Mandatory Scope (Essential Services):</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If your system contributes to any of the following, E27 compliance is effectively mandatory</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Propulsion &amp; Steering:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Engines, thrusters, steering gear</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">50</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Power:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Generation and distribution systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">51</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Safety Systems:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Fire detection, gas detection, watertight doors, bilge, and ballast systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">52</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Navigation &amp; Communication:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Radar, ECDIS, and GMDSS</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">53</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The "Weakest Link" Scope:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Even non-essential systems (e.g., a cargo monitoring unit or HVAC controller) can be pulled into scope if they are connected to the same network as essential systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">54</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Shipyards (System Integrators) will often demand E27 compliance from all connected vendors to prevent a non-critical device from becoming a "backdoor" into the critical vessel network.</span></p>
<h2><strong>3. Real Use Cases: Non-Critical but Mandatory Systems</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For executive leadership, the most common friction point regarding IACS UR E27 is the scope</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It is easy to understand why an Engine Control System needs cyber protection</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It is harder to justify why a Public Address system or a Water Treatment unit requires a cybersecurity certification</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The reality is that regulatory scope is defined by potential impact, not just operational complexity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If a system's failure can endanger the ship, the crew, or the environment—or if it connects to a network that does—it falls under the mandatory requirements</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Below are four real-world examples of systems often categorized as "Tier 2/3" supply that are now fully in scope</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Case A: The Public Address &amp; General Alarm (PA/GA) System</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The System:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Digital PA controllers, talk-back systems, and general alarm panels</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Why it's Mandatory:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While primarily a communication tool, the PA/GA system is a statutory safety requirement under SOLAS (Safety of Life at Sea)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">63</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Regulations explicitly list "internal and external communication systems" as mandatory scope for cyber resilience</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">64</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If the alarm fails during a fire, lives are at risk.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Cyber Risk:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A compromised PA/GA system can be used to trigger false abandon-ship alarms (causing panic and operational stoppage) or be silenced during a real emergency</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Compliance Implication:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You can no longer supply a simple "plug-and-play" digital panel. The system must authenticate users to prevent unauthorized personnel from accessing control menus </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">66</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">and protect integrity to ensure the software running the alarm logic cannot be tampered with</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Case B: Emergency Lighting Control System</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The System:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Programmable controllers for Low Location Lighting (LLL), emergency exit signs, and navigation lights</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">68</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Why it's Mandatory:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Emergency lighting is classified as an </span><strong>Essential Service</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Failure of these systems directly endangers human safety during an evacuation. IACS UR E26 specifically lists "Lighting (e.g., emergency lighting, low locations)" as a target system</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Cyber Risk:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A "blackout" attack where lighting is maliciously disabled during navigation or an emergency event</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Compliance Implication:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Even if the controller is a small embedded box, it is a CBS</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If the controller has a USB maintenance port, it must be physically blocked or logically disabled to prevent malware injection</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">73</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The system must also be capable of a controlled restart to a known safe state after a disruption</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Case C: Ballast Water Treatment System (BWTS)</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The System:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Automated filtration and chemical treatment units used to manage vessel stability and ecology</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Why it's Mandatory:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a critical </span><strong>Environmental Safety</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> system</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. A malfunction can lead to the discharge of invasive species, resulting in heavy fines and detention by Port State Control authorities. "Bilge and ballast systems" are explicitly cited in the regulations</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Cyber Risk:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Manipulation of sensor data to hide non-compliant discharges, or ransomware entering the ship's network via a service technician's laptop connected to the BWTS</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Compliance Implication:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a primary vector for "supply chain" infection</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If a service engineer connects a laptop to update firmware, the BWTS is considered to be interfacing with an "untrusted network"</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The system must have defences (like authentication) to ensure only authorised service tools can connect</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Case D: Refrigerated Cargo (Reefer) Monitoring</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The System:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Remote monitoring units that track temperature, humidity, and power for refrigerated containers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Why it's Mandatory:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While primarily commercial, failure poses a safety risk (fire from overheating units) and massive cargo loss</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. "Cargo handling systems" are defined as in-scope OT systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Cyber Risk:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> These systems are often heavily networked (IoT) to allow remote monitoring from shore. This connectivity creates a "bridge" between the external internet and the ship's internal OT network, making it a prime target for hackers trying to pivot into critical vessel systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Compliance Implication:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The Reefer monitoring system must be strictly segregated from the ship's navigation and propulsion networks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Strict user authentication is required to prevent unauthorized changes to temperature set-points</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>4. The "Paperwork" Burden: What You Must Deliver</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Tier 2 and Tier 3 suppliers, IACS UR E27 is less about "hacking" and more about </span><strong>evidence</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You can no longer simply ship a piece of equipment and claim it is secure; you must prove it through a rigorous documentation package</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This package is the legal basis upon which the Classification Society grants approval and the Shipyard accepts your hardware</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Failure to provide these four core documents is the most common reason for delays in the "Plan Approval" phase</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>4.1 The CBS Asset Inventory (Software Bill of Materials)</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The days of shipping a "black box" are over. Shipyards are now required under UR E26 to maintain a complete inventory of every digital asset on the vessel, and they are contractually forcing suppliers to provide the data for their specific components</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>What is required:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You must submit a granular list of every hardware and software component within your system</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">93</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This is not just a bill of materials; it must include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Hardware:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Manufacturer, model, and physical interfaces (e.g., Network ports, Serial ports, USBs)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Software:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Exact versions and patch levels for the Operating System (e.g., Windows 10 IoT LTSC 2019), firmware, application software, and third-party libraries</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">95</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Executive Insight:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This inventory must be "live." If you ship a spare part or release a firmware update five years from now, you must have a process to update this document</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Without this, the shipowner cannot perform the vulnerability management required by port state authorities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>4.2 The Topology Diagrams</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To integrate your system into the ship's network, the Shipyard needs to understand exactly how your device communicates</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You must provide two specific types of diagrams</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Physical Topology:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A drawing showing the physical architecture—endpoints, cables, network switches, and redundant units</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It must align perfectly with your Asset Inventory</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Logical Topology:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A diagram showing the data flow. You must identify protocols (e.g., Modbus TCP, NMEA 0183), logical connections between virtual machines, and where data enters or leaves your system</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Executive Insight:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Shipyards use these diagrams to design </span><strong>"Security Zones"</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (segmented areas of the network) and firewalls</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If your documentation does not clearly show which ports are open and what protocols are used, the shipyard cannot integrate your system securely, leading to commissioning delays</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>4.3 The "Capabilities" Document (Description of Security Capabilities)</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is your compliance scorecard</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It is a document where you map your system's features to the 30 mandatory security capabilities (and 11 additional ones if connected to untrusted networks) required by UR E27</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">106</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>The Checklist:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> For every requirement (e.g., "User Identification," "Software Integrity," "DoS Protection"), you must explain how your system meets it</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Strategic Loophole: Compensating Countermeasures</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your hardware cannot meet a requirement (e.g., a legacy PLC that cannot support encryption or complex passwords), you do not necessarily need to redesign the product. You can propose a Compensating Countermeasure.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Example:</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> "This device cannot encrypt data, BUT it is intended to be installed inside a locked cabinet (physical control) within a secure network zone (logical control)"</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Condition:</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You must document and prove that this alternative measure provides equivalent protection against the same threat</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>4.4 The Secure Manual (Configuration &amp; Hardening)</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You must shift the "secure configuration" liability to the installer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. UR E27 requires you to provide Security Configuration Guidelines and Hardening Guidelines</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>What is required:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Default Values:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Explicitly state the default passwords and settings</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Hardening Instructions:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Step-by-step instructions for the shipyard or crew on how to "lock down" the device</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This includes changing default passwords, disabling unused ports (e.g., "Turn off Port 80 if web access is not used"), and managing user accounts</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Executive Insight:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This document is your primary defense against liability</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If a cyber incident occurs because the crew left the default password active, your defense is that you provided clear, Class-approved instructions on how to change it</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If you fail to provide this manual, the negligence lies with the manufacturer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">118</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2><strong>5. The Two Paths to Certification</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under IACS UR E27, compliance is ultimately verified per vessel</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, the method by which a supplier proves this compliance varies significantly depending on whether the product is certified in advance. Suppliers must choose between two distinct regulatory pathways. This is a strategic business decision that impacts production costs and delivery timelines</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>5.1 Path A: Type Approval (The Strategic Investment)</strong></h3>
<p><strong>Best for:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Standardized products sold to multiple ships (e.g., Engines, Alarm Systems, Communication Terminals)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>Type Approval</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a voluntary "pre-qualification" process. It is an upfront investment that validates your product's design against UR E27 requirements once, typically covering a 5-year period</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Workflow:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You undergo a rigorous, one-time review by the Classification Society. This involves a full audit of your documentation and a witnessed cyber security test of your hardware at your factory</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Commercial Benefit:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Once Type Approved, your product is effectively "pre-cleared." When a shipyard purchases your equipment for a specific vessel, you are exempted from repeating the exhaustive design review and factory acceptance testing (FAT) for cyber security for that specific ship contract</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Why Shipyards Prefer It:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Shipyards are under pressure to deliver on time</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. A Type Approved system represents low risk, requires less paperwork, and eliminates the scheduling headache of arranging a Class Surveyor for every component</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Executive Takeaway:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Type Approval requires higher initial effort and cost but drastically reduces friction for every subsequent sale, positioning your product as "Plug-and-Play"</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>5.2 Path B: Case-by-Case Approval (The Tactical Fix)</strong></h3>
<p><strong>Best for:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> One-off custom units, highly specialized equipment, or legacy products near end-of-life</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If a product does not hold a Type Approval certificate, it must prove compliance individually for every single vessel it is installed on</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Workflow:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> For every sales contract, you must submit a complete set of cyber security documents to the Class Society. Furthermore, a Class Surveyor must physically attend your factory (or the shipyard) to witness the Cyber Security Factory Acceptance Test (FAT) for that specific unit before it can be accepted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The Operational Risk:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This pathway is operationally expensive. If a surveyor identifies a gap during the witness test, it can delay shipment. Repeatedly generating full documentation packages and paying for surveyor attendance erodes profit margins on high-volume products</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The "Bottleneck" Factor:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> As regulatory deadlines pass, Class Societies are expected to experience backlogs. Reliance on case-by-case approval increases the risk that your documentation will be stuck in a review queue, delaying the shipyard</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Executive Takeaway:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This path minimizes upfront R&amp;D investment but maximizes per-unit cost and administrative burden</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>Summary Comparison Table</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Feature</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Path A: Type Approval</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><strong>Path B: Case-by-Case Approval</strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Initial Investment</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">High (One-time audit &amp; test) </span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Low (No upfront audit) </span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Per-Ship Documentation</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reduced (Minimal set required) </span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Full (Complete dossier required) </span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Surveyor Witnessing</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exempted (for cyber FAT) </span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mandatory (for every unit) </span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Speed to Market</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast (after initial approval)</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Slow (dependent on surveyor availability)</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Shipyard Preference</strong></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">High (Low integration risk)</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Low (Higher admin burden)</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>6. Technical Requirements Simplified (The "Must-Haves")</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While IACS UR E27 contains a list of 30 mandatory security capabilities, executive leadership does not need to memorize every clause. Instead, ensure your product roadmap aligns with four fundamental "Must-Have" principles</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><strong>6.1 Locking the Doors: Identification &amp; Authentication</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The era of "hardcoded" or shared passwords is over. The most common vulnerability in maritime equipment is the use of default credentials (e.g., admin / 1234) that cannot be changed. UR E27 explicitly bans this practice.</span></p>
<p><strong>The Executive Mandate:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>No More Shared Accounts:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Your system must support unique user IDs for different crew members and service technicians</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Force Password Changes:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If your device ships with a default password, the software must force the user to change it upon first login</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You cannot rely on a manual asking them to do it; the system must enforce it technically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>6.2 Identifying the Product: Integrity &amp; Version Control</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shipyards can no longer accept "Black Boxes." They need to know exactly what software is running on your hardware to manage the vessel's risk over 20+ years</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>The Executive Mandate:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Granular Inventory:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Your engineering team must produce a "live" inventory list (Software Bill of Materials) that details every software component, including the Operating System and third-party libraries</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Anti-Tamper Mechanisms:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Your system needs a way to verify that the firmware or software running on it is legitimate, often achieved through "Secure Boot" or digital signatures. If a hacker tries to load malicious firmware, your device should reject it</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>6.3 Checking Health: Diagnostics &amp; Logging</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A silent system is a dangerous system. Under UR E27, your equipment must be "self-aware" enough to report security issues</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>The Executive Mandate:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The "Check Engine" Light for Cyber:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Your system must have a "Security Functionality Verification" feature that alerts the crew if a security function fails (e.g., "Antivirus is disabled" or "Logging has failed")</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Audit Trails:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Every critical action—logging in, changing a set-point, or updating firmware—must be recorded in a log file. These logs must be stored securely so they cannot be deleted by an attacker</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>6.4 Handling "Untrusted" Connections: The Service Laptop Risk</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the single biggest hurdle for Tier 2/3 suppliers. If your equipment allows a service technician to plug in a laptop for maintenance, or if it connects to a remote monitoring gateway, it is communicating with an "Untrusted Network." This triggers a stricter set of requirements</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>The Executive Mandate:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Explicit Human Approval:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A remote user (or a service laptop) cannot just "bridge" into your system. The ship's crew must explicitly approve the connection (e.g., by pressing a button) before access is granted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA):</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If your system allows remote access over the internet, a simple password is no longer sufficient. You must implement MFA (e.g., a token or code sent to a phone) for these connections</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Virus Scanning:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You must ensure that any laptop or USB drive connecting to your system does not introduce malware</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>7. Action Plan for Decision Makers</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The transition to IACS UR E27 compliance is not merely a technical update; it is a market access requirement</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. With the July 1, 2024 regulatory deadline now active, shipyards are actively filtering their supply chains to minimize their own integration risks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Tier 2 and Tier 3 suppliers, the window for "wait and see" has closed. Executive leadership must pivot from awareness to execution</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The following three-step plan provides a roadmap to secure your position on the Approved Vendor List.</span></p>
<h3><strong>7.1 Immediate Audit: Define Your "Cyber Exposure"</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before allocating budget, you must determine exactly which products in your portfolio are liable</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Do not rely on assumptions that your equipment is "too simple" to matter</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>Actionable Steps:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Scan the Product Portfolio:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Review your entire catalog against the IACS definition of a Computer Based System (CBS). If a product contains a programmable microcontroller, firmware, or software, it is technically in scope</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Map Criticality:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Identify which of your products perform or support Essential Services (Propulsion, Steering, Power, Safety). These are your high-risk compliance targets</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Identify Connectivity:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Flag any system that includes a physical interface for data exchange (Ethernet, USB, Serial). Even if intended only for maintenance, these interfaces trigger E27 requirements</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>The "Black Box" Check:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Ask your engineering team if they can produce a granular Asset Inventory (Software Bill of Materials) for these products today. If they cannot list every third-party library, you have a "documentation debt" that must be resolved immediately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ol>
<h3><strong>7.2 Evaluating Business Impact: Type Approval vs. Project-Specific</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you identify the affected products, you must decide on a certification strategy. This is a financial decision: do you pay upfront (CAPEX) to streamline future sales, or pay per project (OPEX) and risk delivery delays? </span></p>
<p><strong>Strategic Decision Matrix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Scenario A: High-Volume / Standard Products:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recommendation:</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Pursue Type Approval (TA) immediately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Shipyards prefer TA components, and you avoid the logistical nightmare of scheduling a surveyor for every single factory acceptance test</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Scenario B: Bespoke / Low-Volume Engineered Systems:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recommendation:</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Use Case-by-Case Approval</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The ROI on Type Approval is low for custom one-offs. However, you must price the cost of documentation and surveyor witnessing into your commercial bid</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Scenario C: Legacy Products (End-of-Life):</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recommendation:</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Develop Compensating Countermeasures</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If a legacy product cannot be re-engineered, qualify it with a documented "wrapper"—such as placing it behind a secure gateway that handles the security functions</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>7.3 Resource Allocation: Engineering vs. Documentation</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most common point of failure for suppliers is underestimating the documentation burden</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Creating the evidence required for Class approval often takes more man-hours than the software changes themselves</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>Executive Directives:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Bridge the IT/OT Gap:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Do not assign this solely to your internal IT department. IT security is different from OT resilience. Your Product Managers and R&amp;D Leads must own the E27 compliance roadmap because it affects product functionality and safety</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Documentation "Sprint":</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Allocate resources specifically for technical writing. Your engineers need to produce Topology Diagrams and Security Capability Statements. If you lack internal capacity, consider outsourcing the "paperwork" phase to specialized maritime cyber consultancies to prevent bottlenecks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Prepare for Supply Chain Transparency:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Shipyards will demand to know your sub-suppliers. Prepare to enforce E27 requirements on the vendors who supply your chips and software libraries, as you are now responsible for the cyber hygiene of the components you integrate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br><br></span></li>
</ol>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
